-=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/=-
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 景鲤
翻译: 爱FAFA的萌 Mabb 司嘉译
翻译: 蓝风 影子 RK翔
校对: 被解救的UU 柚子茶
姜戈
被解救的姜戈
1858年 内战爆发两年前
德州某地
等等 有情况
Whoa.
吁
乌漆麻黑的谁在那鬼鬼祟祟?
Who's that stumblin' around in the dark?
说明你的来意 不然就准备挂彩吧!
State your business or prepare to get winged!
别冲动 先生们
Calm yourselves, gentlemen.
我并无恶意
I mean you no harm.
我只是个疲倦的旅人 停下 孩子
I'm simply a fellow weary traveler. Whoa, boy.
寒冷的晚上好 先生们
Good cold evening, gentlemen.
我在寻找一对奴隶商人
I'm looking for a pair of slave traders
他们自称是斯派克兄弟
that go by the name of the Speck Brothers.
请问是否是阁下?
Might that be you?
- 谁想知道?  - 嗯 我想
- Who wants to know?  - Well, I do.
我是金·舒尔茨医生 这是我的坐骑 小德
I'm Dr. King Schultz. This is my horse, Fritz.
- 什么医生?  - 牙医
- What kinda doctor?  - Dentist.
请问你们是斯派克兄弟吗?
Now, are you the Speck Brothers?
你们是在格林维尔奴隶卖场买下他们的吗?
And did you purchase those men at the Greenville slave auction?
- 是又怎样?  - 那我就有要事相商
- So what?  - So I wish to parley with you.
- 说人话  - 喔 对不起
- Speak English.  - Oh, I'm sorry.
请原谅 那并非我的母语
Please forgive me. It is a second language.
目前 你手里这些存货 我深信里面
Now, amongst your inventory, I've been led to believe,
一定有我需要的货色
is a specimen I'm keen to acquire.
好啊 你们这些可怜的小鬼们!
Hello, you poor devils!
你们之中谁曾经是
Is there one amongst you who was formerly a resident
卡鲁肯农场的人?
of the Carrucan plantation?
我是卡鲁肯农场来的
I'm from the Carrucan plantation.
说话的人在哪?
Who said that?
你叫什么名字?
What's your name?
姜戈
Django.
那我找的就是你了
Then you are exactly the one I'm looking for.
你知道布里托兄弟是谁吗?
Do you know who the Brittle Brothers are?
谁?
Who are they?
大约翰
Big John.
埃利斯
Ellis.
罗杰 有时候也叫做小罗
Roger. Sometime they call him Lil Raj.
他们都曾是卡鲁肯农场的监工
They was overseers at the Carrucan plantation.
他们走了
Not anymore.
告诉我...
Tell me...
如果你再遇到那三位
if you were to see any of these three gentlemen again,
- 你能认出他们吗?  - 嘿
- would you recognize them?  - Hey.
- 别这么跟他说话  - 怎么说?
- Stop talkin' to him like that.  - Like What?
就你这么说
Like that.
我的好兄弟 我只是想核定...
My good man, I'm simply trying to ascertain...
说人话 该死的
Speak English, goddamn it.
都冷静点
Everybody calm down.
我只是个顾客 来做一笔买卖
I'm simply a customer trying to conduct a transaction.
我不在乎 不卖 你走吧
I don't care. No sale. Now, off with ya.
别开玩笑了 他们当然是待售的
Don't be ridiculous. Of course they're for sale.
好狗不挡路
Move it.
我的好兄弟 你这是摆个舞枪弄棒的姿势呢
My good man, did you simply get carried away with your dramatic gesture
还是要动真枪威胁我?
or are you pointing your weapon at me with lethal intention?
再给你一次机会 娘炮
Last chance, fancy pants.
哦 好吧
Oh, very well.
抱歉 射杀了你的牲口
I'm sorry to put a bullet in your beast,
我是怕你还没三思
but I didn't want you to do anything rash
就冲动行事
before you had a moment to come to your senses.
你个狗娘养的!
You goddamn son of a bitch!
- 你杀了罗斯科!  - 好吧...
- You shot Roscoe!  - Well...
- 你还杀了小杰!  - 别急着下定论
- And you killed Ace! -No. No. No.
我杀你哥也是出于自卫
I only shot your brother once he threatened to shoot me.
而且我有... 一 二 三 四...
And I do believe I have... one, two, three, four...
五名目击证人可以佐证
five witnesses who can attest to that fact.
- 腿疼爆了!  - 必然的
- Damn leg's busted!  - No doubt.
好了 请你尽量不要鬼哭狼嚎
Now, if you could keep your caterwauling down to a minimum,
我想最后再问小姜戈几个问题
I'd like to finish my line of inquiry with young Django.
- 天杀的我靠!  - 接着我刚说的...
- God-fuckin'-damn it!  - As I was saying...
要是你再看见布里托兄弟你能认出他们吗?
if you were to see the Brittle Brothers again, you could recognize 'em?
能
Yeah.
成交!
Sold American!
那 斯派克先生? 斯派克? 小姜戈要多少钱?
So, Mr. Speck? Mr. Speck? How much for young Django here?
那个大铁块是最恼人的了
That iron is nasty business.
对了 你能帮我拿一下吗?
Oh, could you hold this for a moment?
谢谢你 姜戈?
Thank you. Django?
上马
Get up on that horse.
还有 要是我是你
Also, if I were you,
我就拿上那个死斯派克身上的大衣
I'd take that winter coat the dear departed Speck left behind.
黑鬼! 你敢动我哥的大衣
Nigger! Don't you touch my brother's coat.
他妈的! 疼!
Goddamn it! Oh!
一百... 一十... 二十...
One hundred... ten... 20...
五块...
and five...
这是小姜戈的
for young Django here.
既然你留着也没什么用
And since he won't be needing it anymore,
我想连你哥的老马一并买下
I'd like to purchase your brother's nag.
还有 斯派克先生 我恐怕还需要一张卖身契
Also, Mr. Speck, I'm afraid I will require a bill of sale.
你有吗?
Do you have one?
去死吧 牙医
You go to hell, dentist.
我猜就没有
I thought not.
别担心 我是有备而来
No worries. I come prepared.
谢谢
Thank you.
就用这个当契约吧
This will serve nicely as a bill of sale.
吁
Whoa.
至于你们这些可怜的小鬼
Now, as to you poor devils.
如此 就我看来 该考虑下一步做什么了
So, as I see it, when it comes to the subject of what to do next,
现在是各位做出选择的时候了
you gentlemen have two choices.
一条路是 我走之后 你们把活的那个斯派克从那牲口身下拽出来
One: Once I'm gone, you could lift that beast off the remaining Speck,
然后把他抬到最近的小镇
then carry him to the nearest town.
就是说得往回走大概至少37英里
Which would be at least 37 miles back the way you came.
第二条路 你们可以把镣铐解开 拿上那把枪
Or two: You could unshackle yourselves, take that rifle,
照着他脑袋上来一枪 然后把他倆的尸骨深埋
put a bullet in his head, bury the two of them deep,
然后找个更开化的地方扎根
and then make your way to a more enlightened area of this country.
供君选择
Choice is yours.
对了 考虑到你们识星象的几率略低
Oh, and on the off chance there are any astronomy aficionados amongst you,
北极星在那边
the North Star is that one.
拜拜啦
Ta-ta.
等等 小伙子们 我们可以谈谈!
Now wait a minute, fellas. Let's talk about this!
你们得讲讲道理!
You gotta be reasonable in a situation like this!
我不是坏人 我只是本分地工作!
I'm not a bad guy. I'm just doin' my job!
蓝莓兄 我最后一个苹果不也给了你吗?
Blueberry, didn't I give you my last apple?
这样吧 孩子们 带我去埃尔帕索城看大夫
Tell you what, boys: Take me to the doc in El Paso,
我就放你们自由
I'll get you your freedom.
不 别 求你们了...
No. No, please...
德州 多特里
好啦 听着
All right, now.
这个今天晚上吃两片...
I'd like you to take two of these tonight...
然后明早...
and then in the morning...
那匹马上有个黑鬼
That's a nigger on a horse.
他们都在看什么?
What's everybody staring at?
他们从来没见过骑着马的黑鬼
They ain't never seen no nigger on a horse before.
吁
Whoa.
早安 老板!
Good morning, innkeeper!
给我们两个疲倦的旅人来两杯啤酒
Two beers for two weary travelers.
现在天色还早吧
It's still a bit early.
我们一个小时之后才开门
We won't be open for another hour.
那时候 我们才提供早餐
By then, we'll be servin' breakfast.
等等 等等 等等... 你这他妈的干什么呢?
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa... what the hell you think you're doing, boy?
把那黑鬼赶出去!
Get that nigger outta here!
- 救命啊! 出大事啦!  - 老板!
- Help! Help!  - Innkeeper!
记得 去叫警长 别叫成司法官了
Remember, get the sheriff, not the marshal.
警长! 救命啊!
Sheriff! Help!
哎
Alas.
我们现在得自己动手了
Now we must act as our own bartender.
坐下吧 孩子
Sit down, my boy.
你是哪门子的牙医?
What kind of dentist are you?
别看那个小车 其实我有五年没出诊了
Despite that cart, I haven't practiced dentistry in five years.
但现在 我已经改行了...
But these days, I practice a new profession...
做赏金猎人
bounty hunter.
你知道什么叫赏金猎人吗?
Do you know what a bounty hunter is?
不知道
No.
好吧...
Well...
就跟奴隶买卖一样 拿人命换钱
the way the slave trade deals in human lives for cash,
赏金猎人是拿尸首换钱
a bounty hunter deals in corpses.
帽子
Hat.
干杯
Prost.
州里提名悬赏人头
The state places a bounty on a man's head.
我追踪 锁定 然后了结他
I track that man, I find that man, I kill that man.
了结他之后 我再把他的尸首运回去鉴定
After I've killed him, I transport that man's corpse back to the authorities.
有时说比做可容易多了
Sometimes that's easier said than done.
我把尸首交给当局 确定一下
I show that corpse to the authorities, proving yes, indeed,
我亲手杀死了他
I truly have killed him,
然后当局再付给我相应的赏金
at which point the authorities pay me the bounty.
所以 就像奴隶买卖 人头换金钱
So, like slavery, it's a flesh for cash business.
什么是赏金?
What's a bounty?
就是奖赏
It's like a reward.
你杀人? 然后他们给你奖赏?
You kill people? And they give you a reward?
某些人 对
Certain people, yeah.
坏人?
Bad people?
对! 他们越坏 奖赏越多
Ah! Badder they are, bigger the reward.
然后我就找上了你
Which brings me to you.
我必须承认 对你呢 我有点进退两难
And I must admit, I'm at a bit of a quandary when it comes to you.
一方面 我鄙视奴隶制度
On one hand, I despise slavery.
另一方面 我实在需要你的帮助
On the other hand, I need your help.
如果你不持反对意见的话 那就太好了
If you're not in a position to refuse, all the better.
所以 那时 我只能借奴隶买卖
So, for the time being, I'm gonna make this slavery malarkey
达到我自己的目的
work to my benefit.
不过 我已经说过了 我深感内疚
Still, having said that, I feel guilty.
因此 我想和你订个君子协议
So, I would like the two of us to enter into an agreement.
我在找布里托兄弟
I'm looking for the Brittle Brothers.
但是 就算我再努力
However, at this endeavor,
不知对方相貌 我显然占了下风
I'm at a slight disadvantage insofar as I don't know what they look like.
但是你认得他们 对吧?
But you do. Don't ya?
我是认得他们的长相
I know what they look like all right.
好 我们就此协定
Good. So here's my agreement.
- 你陪同我 直到我们找到他们  - 我们去哪找?
- You travel with me until we find them.  - Where we goin'?
我听说他们其中至少两个在加特林堡做监工
I hear at least two of them are overseeing up in Gatlinburg,
但是我没有确切地点
but I don't know where.
所以我们要走遍加特林堡的农场去找
That means we visit every plantation in Gatlinburg till we find 'em.
找到他们之后 你把他们指认出来 然后我来了结他们
And when we find them, you point them out, and I kill them.
你只要这么做 我就答应给你自由
You do that, I agree to give you your freedom,
每个人头分你25块 一共75块
$25 per Brittle Brother. That's $75.
果然不出所料 警长来了
And, as if on cue, here comes the sheriff.
好啦 孩子们 闹够了吧 出来吧
OK, boys. Fun's over. Come on out.
好啦 都冷静
All right, folks, calm down.
都该干啥干啥去
Go about your business.
这俩小鬼很快就上路了
These jokers will be gone soon.
告诉我 为什么你们来我的镇子上惹麻烦?
Now, why y'all wanna come into my town and start trouble?
还吓坏了这些老实人
And scare all these nice people.
你们就没点正经事做吗?
You ain't got nothing better to do
净来我比尔·夏普的小镇瞎捣乱
than to come into Bill Sharp's town
简直是自取其辱
and show your ass?
你把我们警长怎么了?
What'd you just do to our sheriff?
你可以去叫司法官了
Now you can get the marshal.
司法官! 司法官!
Marshal! Marshal!
- 我们要不要进去等?  - 咱们走吧?
- Should we wait inside?  - Can we just leave?
你先请
After you.
把路对面的马车横着停边上 对着那家酒馆
Move that buckboard a long ways across the street from the saloon.
然后找六个人拿着来复枪蹲在车后面
I want six men, six rifles behind it.
两个人拿着来复枪上这边房顶
I want two men, two rifles up on this roof.
那边也上去两个
Two men, two rifles on that roof.
所有枪都指着那扇大门
All the barrels aimed at that front door.
来人把可怜的比尔抬走
Somebody get poor Bill outta the goddamn street.
酒吧里的歹徒你听着!
You in the saloon!
你们已经被上百把来复枪包围了
We got a hundred rifles aimed at every way out of that buildin'.
你们只有一次活着出来的机会
You got one chance to get out of this alive.
你和你的黑鬼现在就弃械投降
You and your nigger come out right now with your hands over your head,
就现在
and I mean right now.
是司法官大人亲自来接见我吗?
Is this the marshal I have the pleasure of addressing?
是的
Yes, it is.
我是美国司法官吉尔·塔图姆
This is U.S. Marshal Gill Tatum.
无上荣幸 司法官大人
Na wunderbar, marshal.
我已经正如你说的
I have relieved myself of all weapons,
卸去了所有武器
and just as you have instructed,
我正在以投降的姿态
I am ready to step outside
向外面走来
with my hands raised above my head.
我相信我作为
I trust as a representative
美利坚合众国刑事司法体系的代表
of the criminal justice system of the United States of America,
在上法庭之前是不可以被你和你手下
I shan't be shot down in the street by either you or your deputies
乱枪打死在大街上的
before I've had my day in court.
你是说不可以像你对警长那样
You mean like you did our sheriff.
像条狗似的死在马路中央
Shot him down like a dog in the street.
对 我就是那个意思
Yes, that's exactly what I mean.
你能以执法者的名义承诺 不把我像狗一样射杀在马路中央吗?
Do I have your word as a lawman not to shoot me down like a dog in the street?
好吧 尽管我们都想把你格杀勿论
Well, much as we'd all enjoy seeing something like that,
但我们还都是明察秋毫的
ain't nobody gonna cheat the hangman in my town.
好的 司法官 我们出来了
Fair enough, marshal. Here we come.
他们枪栓都拉得够紧的
They're a little tense out there.
你就别乱来 让我来跟他们说
So don't make any quick movements, and let me do the talking.
出来吧
Come ahead.
赤手空拳啦?
You unarmed?
是 我们都缴械了
Yes, indeed we are.
司法官塔图姆 我能不能向你和你的手下
Marshal Tatum, may I address you and your deputies,
还有在这的整个多特里镇的村民
and apparently the entire town of Daughtrey,
介绍刚刚发生的那场事故?
as to the incident that just occurred?
- 继续  - 多谢
- Go on.  - Thank you.
我的名字是金·舒尔茨医生
My name is Dr. King Schultz.
像你一样 司法官 我也是名执法人员
Like yourself, marshal, I'm a servant of the court.
那黄土中的尸首 比尔·夏普
The man lying dead in the dirt, who the good people of Daughtrey
这位多特里镇的平民选出的警长
saw fit to elect as their sheriff, who went by the name of Bill Sharp,
实际上真名是威拉德·佩克 是个通缉犯
is actually a wanted outlaw by the name of Willard Peck,
被悬赏200块
with a price on his head of $200.
不论生死
Now that's $200, dead or alive.
你说什么!
The hell, you say!
我也深知这是条令人不安的坏消息
I'm aware this is probably disconcerting news.
我敢打赌这个人是在大概两年前
But I'm willing to wager this man was elected sheriff
被选上当警长的?
sometime in the past two years?
对
Yeah.
我知道是因为这个人三年前 在德州卢博克市
I know this because three years ago, he was rustling cattle
BC科里根畜牧公司犯下了偷牛大罪
from the B.C. Corrigan Cattle Company of Lubbock, Texas.
现在 我手拿的是由德州奥斯汀
Now, this is a warrant made out by
巡回法院亨利·亚伦·罗德缪法官签发的逮捕证
Circuit Court Judge Henry Allen Laudermilk of Austin, Texas.
你可以给他发个电报
You're encouraged to wire him.
他会证实我的说辞 揭开你已故的亲爱的警长的真面目
He'll back up who I am and who your dear departed sheriff was.
换句话说 司法官大人 你欠我200块
In other words, marshal, you owe me $200.
见鬼了
I'll be damned.
处理完布里托兄弟之后
After this Brittle business is behind us,
你会得到自由 还有75块进账...
you'll be a free man, with a horse, $75 in your back pocket...
之后你有什么打算?
What's your plan after that?
找到我的妻子 赎回她的自由
Find my wife, and buy her freedom.
姜戈 我还不知道你是已婚男士
Django, I had no idea you were a married man.
大部分奴隶都信婚姻?
Do most slaves believe in marriage?
反正我和我妻子信
Oh, me and my wife do.
卡鲁肯老头不信 所以我们 呃... 跑了出来
Old Man Carrucan didn't. That's why we, uh... we run off.
姜戈
Django.
姜戈 姜戈
Django, Django.
你胆子不小啊 姜戈
You got sand, Django.
这个孩子胆子不小
Boy's got sand.
我偏不喜欢有胆的黑鬼
I got no use for a nigger with sand.
在他脸这儿烙个代表逃跑的r字
I want you to burn a runaway "r" right here on his cheek.
那个女孩也烙上
And the girl, too.
然后把他们带到格林维尔卖场上卖掉
And I want you to take 'em to the Greenville auction and sell 'em.
两个都卖掉
Both of 'em.
分开卖
Separately.
这个嘛...
And this one...
我要你贱卖
you will sell him cheap.
在格林维尔...
In Greenville...
应该有个档案库
there should be some sort of a records office.
记录着她什么时候被卖掉的...
You know when she was sold...
还有她从哪来
you know where she came from,
以及她的名字
and you know her name.
她叫什么来着?
What is her name?
布隆希达
Broomhilda.
- 什么?  - 布隆 希达
- What?  - Broom-hilda.
- 布隆希达?  - 对的
- Broomhilda?  - Hm-mm.
- 她的主人是德国人?  - 对 你怎么知道的?
- Were her owners German?  - Yeah, how you know?
她不是在卡鲁肯农场出生的
She wasn't born on the Carrucan plantation.
她被德国女主人养大 沙夫特家
She was raised by a German mistress, the Von Shafts.
她也会说一点德语
She speak a little German, too.
- 你妻子?  - 嗯
- Your wife?  - Hm-mm.
她还小的时候 女主人教过她
When she was little, her mistress taught her so she'd have somebody
为了能有个人说说话
to speak German with.
好了 我来理一遍
Well, let me get this straight.
你的奴隶妻子会说德语 而且她叫布隆希达·沙夫特?
Your slave wife speaks German and her name is Broomhilda Von Shaft?
对
Yep.
他们叫我希达
They call me Hildi.
田纳西州
进这些农场之后 我们要演场戏
When we gain access to these plantations, we'll be putting on an act.
你有自己的角色要扮演
You'll be playing a character.
怎么样?
Hm?
不好看啊?
No?
表演的时候 你不能出戏
During the act, you can never break character.
你明白么?
Do you understand?
嗯 不出戏
Yeah. Don't break character.
你的角色就是随从
And your character is that of The Valet.
什么意思?
What that is?
说不好听的就是仆人
That's a fancy word for servant.
- 随从?  - 嗯
- Valet?  - Hm-mm.
现在嘛 姜戈 你可以为你的角色选戏服了
And now, Django, you may choose your character's costume.
你让我给我自己选衣服?
Youse gonna let me pick out my own clothes?
那是自然
But of course.
吁
Whoa.
在这里黑鬼骑马是犯法的
It's against the law for niggers to ride horses in this territory.
他是我的随从 他不走路的
This is my valet. My valet does not walk.
- 我是说在马上的这黑鬼...  - 他的名字是姜戈
- I said niggers on horses...  - His name is Django.
他是自由的 他想骑什么就骑什么
He's a free man. He can ride what he pleases.
在我的地盘可不行 至少在我的黑鬼面前 不行
Not on my property. Not around my niggers, he can't.
这位先生 我想我们误会了
My good sir, perhaps we got off on the wrong boot.
请容我解释
Allow me to unring this bell.
我是金·舒尔茨医生 这是我的随从姜戈
My name is Dr. King Schultz. This is my valet, Django.
这是我们的坐骑托尼和小德
And these are our horses, Tony and Fritz.
班尼特先生?
Mr. Bennett?
我听说您是一位绅士 也是位生意人
I've been led to believe that you are a gentleman and a businessman.
因此我们才骑马从德州来到了田纳西州
And it is for these attributes we've ridden from Texas to Tennessee
与您会面
to parley with you now.
我想从你这里买一个女奴
I wish to purchase one of your nigger gals.
你和你的小喽啰从德州来到田纳西
You and your Jimmie rode from Texas to Tennessee
就是为了买我一个女奴?
to buy one of my nigger gals?
不事先打个招呼 啥也没有就来了?
No appointment, no nothin'?
噢 的确如此
Oh, I'm afraid so.
嗯 那如果我说我不喜欢你呢?
Well, what if I was to say I don't like you?
还有你的小丑黑鬼?
Or your fancy-pants nigger?
我什么都不打算卖给你
And I wouldn't sell you a tinker's damn.
你想说什么吗?
Now what you got to say about that?
班尼特先生
Mr. Bennett.
如果您真如传闻中说的那样具有商业头脑的话
If you are the businessman I've been led to believe you to be,
我有五千个理由可以改变您的想法
I have 5,000 things I might say that could change your mind.
哦 快进屋来喝点冷饮吧
Well, come on inside and get yourself somethin' cool to drink.
嗯
Hm-mm.
哦 我们谈生意的时候
Oh, maybe while we discuss business,
是否可以请您安排一个可爱的黑奴
you could provide one of your loveliest black creatures
带姜戈上你这大农场四处转转呢
to escort Django here around your magnificent grounds.
哦 当然 没问题! 贝提娜
Oh, well, absolutely! Uh, Betina.
- 有啥吩咐 老爹?  - 呃...
- Yessir, Big Daddy?  - Uh...
你的小喽啰叫什么来着?
What's your Jimmie's name again?
- 姜戈  - 对 姜戈
- Django.  - Django.
贝提娜 带着这位姜戈
Betina, sugar, could you take Django there
带他在周围转转看看我们的好东西
and take him around the grounds here and show him all the pretty stuff.
遵命 老爹
As you please, Big Daddy.
哦 班尼特先生 请允许我提醒你一下 姜戈是个自由人
Oh, Mr. Bennett, I must remind you, Django is a free man.
他可不能被当作奴隶对待 他... 鉴于这里的气氛这么好
He cannot be treated like a slave. He... within the bounds of good taste,
他必须得到与我同等的对待
he must be treated as an extension of myself.
- 了解 舒尔茨 贝提娜亲爱的  - 有啥吩咐?
- Understood, Schultz. Betina, sugar?  - Yes'm?
姜戈不是奴隶 姜戈是自由人 你明白吗?
Django isn't a slave. Django is a free man, you understand?
你可不能像对待这里的其他黑鬼那样对待他
You can't treat him like any of the other niggers around here,
因为他与这里的其他黑鬼不一样 明白么?
'cause he ain't like any of the other niggers around here. You got it?
你让我像对待白人那样对待他?
You want I should treat him like white folks?
不 我没这么说
No. That's not what I said.
那你是什么意思呢 老爹
Then I don't know what you want, Big Daddy.
嗯 让我想想 呃...
Yes, I can see that. Uh...
那个从镇子里来的干活戴眼镜的伐木工叫什么名字来着?
What's the name of that peckerwood boy from town that works with the glass?
他妈在锯木场工作的那个
His mama work over at the lumberyard.
- 哦 你是说杰瑞  - 就是他 杰瑞!
- Oh, you mean Jerry.  - That's the boy's name. Jerry!
知道杰瑞吧 知道吗 亲爱的?
You know Jerry, don't you, sugar?
- 知道 老爹  - 那就好
- Yes'm, Big Daddy.  - Well, that's it, then.
你就像对待杰瑞那样对待他好了
You just treat him like you would Jerry.
我们刚离开的那屋子叫大房子
That house we just left from is The Big House.
因为它大所以老爹这么称呼它
Big Daddy call it that 'cause it's big.
那边是粮仓
That there is the pantry.
老爹在那边晾干肉
That's where Big Daddy hang all his dead meat.
可怜的小松鼠们
Po' little squirrels.
你都为主人做些啥?
What you do for your massa?
你没听他说我不是奴隶吗?
Didn't you hear him tell you I ain't no slave?
- 你真的是自由人?  - 对 我是
- So you really free?  - Yes, I's free.
你是自己打扮成这样的?
You mean you wanna dress like that?
- 贝提娜 我要问你些事情  - 你想干嘛?
- Betina, I need to ask you somethin'.  - What you want?
我在找三个白人 三兄弟 监工
I'm lookin' for three white men. Three brothers. Overseers.
他们姓布里托 你认识他们吗?
Their name is Brittle. You know 'em?
- 布里托?  - 对 布里托
- Brittle?  - Yes, Brittle.
约翰 埃利斯和罗杰 有时候也叫小罗
John Brittle, Ellis Brittle, Roger Brittle, sometime called Lil Raj.
不认识
I don't know them.
他们也可能用假名字
They could be usin' a different name.
应该是去年来农场的
They woulda come to the plantation this past year.
- 你是说谢弗一家?  - 也许吧
- You mean the Shaffers?  - Maybe.
- 三兄弟?  - 嗯嗯
- Three brothers?  - Uh-huh.
- 在这吗?  - 在啊
- They here?  - Uh-huh.
给我指指其中一个?
Could you point one of 'em out to me?
嗯 其中一个就在那边地里
Well, one's over in that field.
卡鲁肯老头子不会同意这么干的
Old Man Carrucan ain't gonna appreciate this, now.
她是在屋里干活的 约翰
She work in the house, John.
你会把她的皮肤弄坏 你会把她弄伤的
You could mess her skin up, and you gonna mess her up
她就不值... 不值一分钱了
and she ain't gonna be worth... she ain't gonna be worth a damn thing.
你们的圣经不是说...
Now, your Bible say...
瞧 我告诉你了 是我让他那么干的
Look, I told you that I was one that made her do it.
准备好了吗?
You ready?
她并不想跟我一起逃 要是有人该挨鞭子
She didn't wanna run off with me. If anybody should be gettin' whupped now,
应该是我 应该是我 约翰
it should be me. It should be me, John.
我来了很久了 你了解我的 你知道我的
Now, I been here long enough, you know me, you know me a long time, now.
你知道卡鲁肯主人是不同意这样做的
You know Massa Carrucan ain't gonna appreciate this.
她是在屋里伺候人的
She's a... she's a house slave.
她是在屋里伺候人的 她不能被...
She a house slave, she can't be...
我跪下了 我在请求您 这不是你想要的吗?
On my knees. I'm asking you this, please. Ain't this what you want?
我来给你取乐吧 约翰 求你了
I'm keeping it funny for you. Now, John, please.
我给你跪下了 约翰
L's on my knees, John.
我喜欢你乞求的样子 小子
I like the way you beg, boy.
是你要找的人吗?
Is that who you was lookin' for?
没错
Yep.
另外两个呢?
Where the other two at?
在马厩那边 在惩罚打破了鸡蛋的小乔迪
They by the stable, punishin' Little Jody for breakin' eggs.
鞭打小乔迪?
They whippin' Little Jody?
给我指指方向
Point me in that direction.
朝树走 然后往那边走
You go to that tree and keep goin' that-a way.
去找和我一起的那个白人
Go get that white man I came here with.
- 来吧  - 不 不 求你了!
- Come on, now.  - No, no, please!
- 来吧 贱人  - 求你了!
- Come on, girlie.  - Please!
来吧 把你绑好了
Come on. Get you set up now.
"耶和华说 凡你所惧怕的..."
"And the Lord said, The fear of ye..."
"和你所担忧的"
"and the dread of ye
将应在大地上的一切野兽身上"
shall be on every beast of the earth."
给我过来 女人!
Come here now, woman!
胳膊给我伸出来!
You'd better give me that arm!
好了 她准备好了!
OK, she's ready!
从今往后 看你还敢不敢打碎鸡蛋
And after this, we'll see if you break eggs again.
嘿 约翰·布里托!
John Brittle!
还记得我吗?
You remember me?
我喜欢你死掉的样子 小子
I like the way you die, boy.
你这狗娘养的!
Goddamn son of a bitch!
好玩吧!
Keep it funny!
你们想看好戏吗?
Y'all wanna see somethin'?
不!
No!
这俩是谁?
Who were they?
这是大约翰 这是小罗
That's Big John, and that's Lil Raj.
埃利斯呢?
Where's Ellis?
他正骑着高头大马在地里监工呢
He's the one high tailin' it across that field right now.
- 真是他?  - 没错
- You sure that's him?  - Yeah.
- 确定吗?  - 不知道
- Positive?  - I don't know.
- 不知道能否确定?  - 不知道什么叫"确定"
- You don't know if you're positive?  - I don't know what "positive" mean.
- 你能肯定是他吗?  - 能
- It means you're sure.  - Yes.
- 能什么?  - 能肯定那就是埃利斯·布里托
- "Yes," what?  - Yes, I'm sure that's Ellis Brittle.
我确定他死了
I'm positive he dead.
姜戈!
Django!
请大家冷静
Everybody calm down.
我们不会再造成伤亡
We mean no one else any harm.
你俩到底是什么人?
Who are you two jokers?
我是金·舒尔茨医生
I am Dr. King Schultz, a legal representative
美利坚合众国的刑事司法系统的法定代表
of the criminal justice system of the United States of America.
我左边这位是姜戈·弗里曼(自由人) 是我的助手
The man to my left is Django Freeman. He's my deputy.
我的口袋里有张逮捕证
In my pocket is a warrant,
是德州奥斯汀的巡回法院亨利·亚伦·罗德缪法官签发的
signed by Circuit Court Judge Henry Allen Laudermilk of Austin, Texas,
授权我抓捕这三个人 不论死活
for the arrest and capture, dead or alive,
他们是约翰·布里托 罗杰·布里托 和埃利斯·布里托
of John Brittle, Roger Brittle and Ellis Brittle.
现在他们改姓了谢弗
They were goin' by the name Shaffer.
你们认识的谢弗兄弟 其实这几个凶手姓布里托
You know them by the name of Shaffer, but the butchers' real name was Brittle.
他们是被通缉的人
These are wanted men.
他们的罪名是谋杀
The law wants 'em for murder.
现在 我重申一下 通缉令说死活不限
Now, I reiterate, the warrant states dead or alive,
因此弗里曼先生和我发现他们的踪迹
so when Mr. Freeman and myself executed these men on sight,
并将他们击毙是依法办事
we were operating within our legal boundaries.
我知道你们对此很不高兴
I realize passions are high,
但是我必须警告你们
but I must warn you, the penalty for taking deadly force
对正在执法的执法者诉诸致命武力的人
against an officer of the court in the performance of his duty
将被判绞刑
is you'll be hung by the neck until you're dead.
现在 我可以从兜里拿出我的逮捕证好让你检查一下吗?
Now, may I please remove the warrant from my pocket so you may examine it?
拿来
Gimme.
可以了吧?
Satisfied?
我能拿回来了吗 谢谢?
May I have that back, please?
- 离开我的地界  - 立即照办
- Get off my land.  - Posthaste.
收拾好尸体 我们马上离开这里
Load up the bodies as quickly as you can and let's get outta here.
好极了 就那俩狗娘养的
Yeah, that's them sons-a-bitches.
冲啊 兄弟们!
Come on, men!
- 我们是来弄死你的 黑鬼!  - 咦哈!
- We're coming for you, nigger!  - Hee-haw!
听好 除非他们先开枪 我们不能先开枪
Now, unless they start shootin' first, nobody shoot 'em.
这两个家伙可不能这么轻易就死了
That's way too simple for these jokers.
我们要抽死那个喜欢黑鬼的家伙
We're gonna whup that nigger-lover to death.
我要亲自撕碎那个死黑鬼
And I'm gonna personally strip and clip that garboon myself.
该死
Damn.
戴着这个我啥都看不见了
I can't see fuckin' shit outta this thing.
准备好了吗?
We ready or what?
噢等等 眼睛上这个洞要弄弄
Aw, hold on, I'm fuckin' with my eyeholes.
噢... 哦 该死
Oh... Oh, shit.
弄得更糟了
I just made it worse.
这破玩意谁做的?
Who made this goddamn shit?
- 威拉德的老婆弄的  - 怎么啦 嫌不好自己去做!
- Willard's wife.  - Well, make your own goddamn masks!
瞧 大家很感激珍妮为我们做的一切
Look, nobody's sayin' they don't appreciate what Jenny did.
不过 只不过是在口袋上弄两个眼儿出来
Well, if all I had to do was cut a hole in a bag,
要是我弄 肯定比这强!
I coulda cut it better than this!
罗伯特 你怎么样? 能看到吗?
What about you, Robert? Can you see?
勉强吧
Not too good.
我是说 脑袋不动的话多少还能看到些
I mean, if I don't move my head I can see you pretty good, more or less.
但是骑马跑起来 口袋就到处乱晃 两眼一抹黑
But when I start ridin', the bag's movin' all over, and I'm ridin' blind.
- 该死  - 就是
- Shit.  - Yeah.
我把我的弄得更糟了
I just made mine worse.
天啊
Oh, God.
有人带了多余的口袋吗?
Anybody bring any extra bags?
没人带着多余的口袋!
No, nobody brought an extra bag!
我就想问问
I'm just askin'.
骑马的时候一定要戴吗?
Do we have to wear 'em when we ride?
废话!
Oh, well, shitfire!
骑马的时候不戴还有什么意义!
If you don't wear 'em as you ride up, that just defeats the purpose!
问题是戴着这个我什么都看不到!
Well, I can't see in this fuckin' thing!
戴着这玩意我喘不过气啊 我不能戴着它骑马!
I can't breathe in this fuckin' thing and I can't ride in this fuckin' thing!
谁管你们! 我要回家了!
Well, fuck all y'all! I'm goin' home!
我老婆忙了一整天做了30个口袋
Now, I watched my wife work all day gettin' 30 bags together
给你们这些不感恩的杂种
for you ungrateful sons-a-bitches,
我听到除了抱怨就是抱怨还有抱怨!
and all I can hear is criticize, criticize, criticize!
从今往后 别指望我帮你们办事了!
From now on, don't ask me or mine for nothin'!
听着 别忘了我们是来干嘛的
Now, look, let's not forget why we're here.
山那边有个黑鬼杀手呢!
We got a killer nigger over that hill there!
我们要给他点颜色看看
And we gotta make a lesson out of him.
好吧 我有点乱 到底罩不罩口袋?
OK, I'm confused. Are the bags on or off?
我们不是一致认为罩口袋是好主意吗?
I think we all think the bag was a nice idea.
好吧
Yeah.
不过 没有特指谁啊 这手艺可真不怎么样
But, not pointin' any fingers, they coulda been done better.
那这次不戴可以吗
So how 'bout no bags this time,
下次我们改良一下 再戴怎么样
but next time we do the bags right and then we go full regalia.
- 这主意我喜欢  - 投你一票 罗伯特
- I like that idea a lot.  - You get my vote, Robert.
等等 我没说不罩口袋
Wait a minute! I didn't say no bags.
但是大家都看不见啊
But nobody can see.
那又怎么了?
So?
看得见比较好吧
So it'd be nice to see.
该死的! 我们是突袭! 我看不到 你也看到不到!
Goddamn it! This is a raid! I can't see, you can't see!
那又怎么了? 该死的马能看到不就得了! 突袭吗不是!
So what? All that matters is can the fuckin' horse see! That's a raid!
根本看不清!
I can't see shit!
他在这! 从车厢下面把那黑鬼拖出来!
There he is! Get that nigger out from under that wagon!
从车里把黑鬼爱好者也弄出来!
And get that nigger-lover outta the wagon!
黑鬼不在这里 老爹!
That nigger ain't down here, Big Daddy!
- 什么?  - 他们耍了我们!
- What?  - They tricked us!
那 那他们在哪?
Well, where are they?
再会
Auf Wiedersehen.
噢!
Oh!
十环
Bull's-eye.
他们逃跑了
Look at 'em run.
一群懦夫就是这样
Yeah, cowards tend to do that.
该死的!
Goddamn it!
你来试试?
Would you care to?
罩着这玩意什么都看不到!
Can't see shit outta this!
- 他要逃了  - 我瞄到了
- He's getting away.  - I got him.
老爹要逃了
Big Daddy's getting away.
我瞄准了
I got him.
干掉他了
Got him.
很有天赋啊
The kid's a natural.
你怎么知道布隆希达的第一个主人是德国人?
How you know Broomhilda's first masters was German?
布隆希达是个德国名字
Broomhilda is a German name.
既然给她起这个名字 他们应该是德国人
If they named her, it stands to reason they'd be German.
你们那里很多女孩都叫布隆希达吗?
Lots of gals where you're from named Broomhilda?
布隆希达在德国是一个家喻户晓的名字
Broomhilda is the name of a character
她是一个德国传说中的人物
in the most popular of all the German legends.
布隆希达还有个故事?
There's a story about Broomhilda?
是的 有个故事
Oh, yes, there is.
- 你知道这故事?  - 每个德国人都知道
- Do you know it?  - Oh, every German knows that story.
想让我给你讲讲?
Would you like me to tell you?
嗯 布隆希达是个公主
Well, Broomhilda was a princess.
她是万神之神沃坦的女儿
She was a daughter of Wotan, god of all gods.
不过 她父亲对她很恼火
Anyway, her father is really mad at her.
她干什么了?
What she do?
记不清了
I can't exactly remember.
反正就是违抗了他父亲的命令
She disobeys him in some way.
所以他把关在一座山的山顶
So he puts her on top of the mountain.
布隆希达在山里?
Broomhilda's on a mountain?
这是德国传说
It's a German legend,
总是有个山什么的
there's always going to be a mountain in there somewhere.
他还安排了喷火龙守卫那座山
And he puts a fire-breathing dragon there to guard the mountain.
用地狱之火围绕着她
And he surrounds her in a circle of hellfire.
因此 布隆希达只好那么待着
And there, Broomhilda shall remain.
除非有一位勇士能来拯救她
Unless a hero arises brave enough to save her.
有么?
Does a fella arise?
有啊 姜戈 实际上 他真的去了
Yes, Django, as a matter of fact, he does.
一个叫齐格弗里德的小伙子
A fella named Siegfried.
齐格弗里德救到她了吗?
Does Siegfried save her?
他做到了 很了不起
Quite spectacularly so.
他爬上了大山 因为他无所畏惧
He scales the mountain, because he's not afraid of it.
他杀死了恶龙 因为他无所畏惧
He slays the dragon, because he's not afraid of him.
他穿越了地狱之火...
And he walks through hellfire...
因为布隆希达值得这么做
because Broomhilda's worth it.
我了解他的感觉
I know how he feel.
我觉得我刚刚才了解到
I think I'm just starting to realize that.
嗯 听着 姜戈...
Now, look, Django...
我毫不怀疑你会去拯救你的爱人...
I don't doubt that one day you'll save your lady love...
但我从心里不希望你去格林维尔
but I can't let you go to Greenville in a good conscience.
密西西比的奴隶市场可不适合你啊
A slave auction town in Mississippi isn't the place for you to visit.
不论你是不是自由人 那都很危险
Free or not, it's just too dangerous.
让我来问你一个问题
But let me ask you a question.
你喜欢当赏金猎人吗?
How do you like the bounty hunting business?
杀白人还有钱拿?
Kill white folks and they pay you for it?
怎么会不喜欢?
What's not to like?
我得承认 我俩搭档很不错
Now, I have to admit, we make a good team.
我以为我杀了大约翰和小罗让你很不高兴呢
I thought you was mad at me for killin' Big John and Lil Raj.
没错 那种场合下你是有点过分了
Yeah, on that occasion you were a tad overzealous,
不过一般来说 那也没什么
but normally, that's a good thing.
我们搭伙干一个冬天怎么样?
How'd you like to partner up for the winter?
搭伙是什么意思?
What you mean "partner up"?
整个冬天直到冰雪融化你跟着我...
You work with me through the winter till the snow melts...
奖金我分你三分之一
I give you a third of my bounties.
我们这个冬天赚些钱 等雪化了
So we make some money this winter, and when the snow melts,
我亲自带你去格林维尔
I'll take you to Greenville myself
我们去找你妻子的下落
and we'll find where they sent your wife.
你为什么这么关心我?
Why you care what happen to me?
为什么关心我是否找得到妻子?
Why you care if I find my wife?
坦白说...
Frankly...
我从没有给过谁自由之身
I've never given anybody their freedom before.
现在我给了你自由 我觉得我对你负有一定的责任
And now that I have, I feel vaguely responsible for you.
再说 一个德国人遇到了现实中的齐格弗里德 没理由不帮一把的
Plus, when a German meets a real life Siegfried, that's kind of a big deal.
作为一个德国人 我有义务帮你
As a German, I'm obliged to help you on your quest
拯救你的爱人布隆希达
to rescue your beloved Broomhilda.
注意点
You got her.
哦 杀白人挣钱先生 你怎么了?
Ooh. What happened to Mr. "I Wanna Shoot White Folks For Money"?
- 他儿子也在那  - 嗯 很好
- His son's with him.  - Well, good.
他有个挚爱亲人在身边
He'll have a loved one with him.
也许还能留句遗言
Maybe even share a last word.
比其他人强多了
That's better than most of them get.
坏人不应该有这种好报
Damn sight better than he deserves.
枪放下吧
Put down the rifle.
别怕 我没生你的气
Don't worry, I'm not mad at you.
我们拿出斯密·巴考尔的通缉令
Let's take out Smitty Bacall's handbill.
大声读出来
Read it aloud.
就当是今天的功课
Consider that today's lesson.
通缉 无论死活
Wanted. Dead or alive.
斯密·巴考尔以及斯密·巴考尔的
Smitty Bacall and the Smitty Bacall
- 团伙  - 团伙
- Gang.  - Gang.
因谋杀以及打劫...
For murder and stagecoach...
驿站马车
robbery.
- 七 零 零 零...  - 七千
- Seven-zero-zero-zero...  - Seven thousand.
千
Thousand.
悬赏七千美元捉拿斯密·巴考尔
$7,000 for Smitty Bacall.
一千五百美元捉拿他的每个...
$1,500 for each of his...
团伙...
gang...
- 成...  - 成员
- Mem...  - Members.
已知的斯密·巴考尔团伙成员于下:
Known members of the Smitty Bacall Gang are as follas:
- 如下  - 如下
- Follows.  - Follows.
丹迪·迈克尔斯 杰拉尔德·纳什和...
Dandy Michaels, Gerald Nash and...
疯子克雷格·昆斯
Crazy Craig Koons.
这才是斯密·巴考尔的真面目
That is who Smitty Bacall is.
他要是22岁开始老实经营农场
If Smitty Bacall wanted to start a farm at 22,
就不会被印在这上面了
they would never have printed that.
可斯密·巴考尔想抢劫马车
But Smitty Bacall wanted to rob stagecoaches
为达目的他不惜杀人
and he didn't mind killing people to do it.
你想做我的工作来挣钱救你妻子吗?
Do you want to save your wife by doing what I do?
这就是我的工作
This is what I do.
我杀人 用尸体换赏金
I kill people and sell their corpses for cash.
这具尸体值七千美元
This corpse is worth $7,000.
别婆婆妈妈了 朝他开枪
Now quit your pussyfooting and shoot him.
爸爸?
Pa?
爸爸!
Pa!
拿着
Here.
你得保管好这斯密·巴考尔的通缉令
You need to keep this Smitty Bacall handbill.
- 为什么?  - 这是好运气
- Why?  - It's good luck.
要保存好第一份赏金通缉令
You always keep the handbill of your first bounty.
非常准
That's accurate.
医生 姜戈 你们好啊?
Doctor, Django, how the hell are ya?
那些又是谁啊?
Who the hell-a you got there?
威尔逊劳团伙
The Wilson-Lowe Gang.
什么威尔逊劳团伙?
Who the hell is the Wilson-Lowe Gang?
坏蛋查克·威尔逊 更坏的鲍比·劳和三个随从
Bad Chuck Wilson and meaner Bobby Lowe and three of their acolytes.
哦 就放这儿吧 他们也跑不了了
Huh. Well, just leave 'em out here, they ain't going nowhere.
你们别在雪里待着 进屋来
Why don't you come in then out of the snowy snow
喝点咖啡
and get yourselves some coffee.
昨天有人过生日 剩了点蛋糕
We had a birthday yesterday. Got some cake.
相当不错的蛋糕
Pretty good.
在一个寒冷但收获颇丰的冬天后
姜戈和舒尔茨医生双双下山 去往...
往前走!
Move along!
密西西比州
走啊 黑鬼!
Move it, boy!
跟上了
Keep movin'.
到那个拍卖台上去
Get on up on that auction block.
别让泥土拖慢你们的步伐 继续前进
Don't let that mud slow you down. Keep going.
继续前行!
Keep goin'!
"布隆希达·沙夫特 27岁
"Broomhilda Von Shaft. Age 27,
右脸有'r'型标志"
'r' on right cheek."
卖给了卡尔文·坎迪
Calvin Candie.
他拥有密西西比第四大棉花种植园: 糖果农场
He owns the fourth biggest cotton plantation in Mississippi: Candyland.
糖果农场?
Candyland?
哦 那你听说过了
Oh, so you've heard of it.
没有哪个奴隶不知道糖果农场
Ain't no slave ain't heard of Candyland.
那么 很显然 你妻子就在那...
Well, apparently, that's where your wife is...
这就是她讨厌的主人
and that's the repellant gentleman
希望她在房子里工作 而不是在田地里
who owns her. Let's just hope she works in the house, not in the field.
哦 不 她不会在田地干活的
Oh, no, she ain't no field nigger.
她... 她很漂亮
She... she pretty.
而且也很会说话
And she talk good, too.
但他们鞭打了她后背 然后...
But when they tore her back up and then they...
还在她的脸上印了逃跑的"r"字母...
burned that runaway "r" on her cheek...
他们诅咒了她
they goddamned her.
她不是田农 但也没好到
She ain't no field nigger but she ain't good enough
可以料理房内家务
for the house no more either.
他们肯定会让她做情妇
They gonna try to make her a comfort girl.
什么是情...? 噢
What's a comfort...? Oh.
我有自由就绝对不容许
Not while I got freedom.
我有了枪也绝不容许
Not while I got my gun.
那我们要出价买她?
So do we offer to buy her?
那么...
So...
假设...
say...
一个人想买马
a man wants to buy a horse.
得买一匹马
Needs to buy a horse.
他走向农场 敲场主的门
He walks up to the farmer's farm, and he knocks on the farmer's door
问场主买马
and asks the farmer to buy his horse.
你知道主人怎么说吗?
And do you know what the farmer says?
他会拒绝
The farmer says no.
那我说去他妈的场主 我要偷那匹马
Well, I say fuck that farmer, and I'm stealin' that horse.
有道理 但那样你就成了窃马贼 会被绞死的
Fair enough. But now you're a horse thief, and they hang horse thieves.
更别说马儿还是会回到主人身边
Not to mention the horse goes back to its original owner
因为马仍是他的财产
because the horse is still his property.
我们需要她 也要一张卖身契
We need her and we need a bill of sale.
那如果我们不买她 该如何得到?
Well, if we ain't gonna try to buy her, then how we gonna get her?
我可以提供B计划吗?
May I offer an alternative plan of action?
说吧
Go ahead.
那么... 他走向农场
So... the man walks up to the farmer's farm,
敲农场主的门...
he knocks on the farmer's door...
向场主买农场 而不是马
and asks not to buy the horse, but the farm.
开出个惊天报价
And makes an offer so ridiculous,
场主就不得不答应了
the farmer is forced to say yes.
- 我们说买糖果农场?  - 不 那太贵了
- We gonna offer to buy Candyland?  - No, it's far too big.
但显然 农场不是这位场主的全部
But apparently this farmer ain't all about the farm.
你对曼丁哥拳击了解多少?
How much do you know about Mandingo fighting?
什么?
What?
你能不能巧妙伪装成
Can you convincingly masquerade as someone
曼丁哥拳击的高手?
who is an expert on Mandingo fighting?
为什么?
Why?
因为我要扮演一个来自杜塞尔多夫的阔绰买家
Because my character is that of a big money buyer from Dusseldorf,
到格林维尔想买通进入曼丁哥拳击的道路
here in Greenville to buy my way into the Mandingo fight game.
你要扮演我聘请来的曼丁哥专家
And your character is a Mandingo expert I hired to help me do it.
人们叫他"独眼查理"
They call that "One-Eyed Charley."
您好
Bonjour.
我们是来见卡尔文·坎迪先生的
We're here to see Mr. Calvin Candie.
请进
Entraz.
- 谢谢你  - 嗯哼
- Thank you.  - Hm-mm.
你要我扮演奴隶贩?
You want me to play a black slaver?
没什么比黑奴贩更低贱了
Ain't nothin' lower than a black slaver.
黑奴贩要比黑人管家还低下...
A black slaver is lower than the head house nigger...
哥们 那可够低贱的
and, buddy, that's pretty fuckin' low.
那就照那样子演
Then play him that way.
把你奴隶贩那一面展示出来
Give me your black slaver.
219路的嘟嘟声也来了! 花生酱!
Along came the 219 Toot! Toot! Peanut butter!
舒尔茨医生!
Dr. Schultz!
- 再次见面太高兴了!  - 莫吉先生
- Good to see you again!  - Mr. Moguy.
感谢你帮我营造机会
Thank you for your assistance in creating the opportunity
- 能有这次会面  - 何足挂齿 是我该做的
- for this appointment.  - Nonsense, it's my job.
那么这就是我久仰大名的独眼查理了
So this is the One-Eyed Charley I've heard so much about.
是的 这位是姜戈·弗里曼
Yes, this is Django Freeman.
姜戈 这是坎迪先生的律师 莱奥妮德·莫吉先生
Django, this is Mr. Candie's lawyer, Leonide Moguy.
叫我莱奥就行了
Just call me Leo.
卡尔文在凯撒大帝室 你要跟我来吗?
Calvin's in the Julius Caesar room. You all wanna follow me?
你和坎迪先生共事多久了?
How long have you been associated with Mr. Candie?
哦 大约11岁时 我和卡尔文的父亲
Oh, Calvin's father and I were about 11
一起去读的寄宿学校
when we went to boarding school together.
卡尔文的爷爷安排我进法学院
Calvin's father's father put me through law school.
只能说我是注定要成为卡尔文家的律师
One could almost say I was raised to be Calvin's lawyer.
也可以说你是个黑鬼
One could almost say youse a nigger.
你说什么?
What did you say?
- 我说...  - 没什么 他就是莽撞了点
- I said...  - Nothing, he's just being cheeky.
见坎迪先生之前 还有我应该知道的其他事情吗?
Uh, anything else about Mr. Candie that I should know before I meet him?
有 他有点法国崇拜
Yes, he is a bit of a Francophile.
哪个文明人不是呢?
What civilized people aren't?
比起坎迪先生他更喜欢法语式的先生坎迪
And he prefers Monsieur Candie to Mr. Candie.
随他的意愿啦(法语)
他不会说法语 别跟他说法语 会使他难堪
He doesn't speak French. Don't speak French to him, it'll embarrass him.
快站起身来! 转过身!
Get back on top, now! Turn around!
就这样
There you go.
就是这样
你为什么想介入曼丁哥生意?
Why do you want to get in the Mandingo business?
你不打算让你的副手做个适当的介绍吗?
You don't intend to allow your second to make the proper introductions?
别拖延时间
Quit stalling, now.
回答我的问题
Answer the question.
无奈的真相? 我很无聊
The awful truth? I'm bored.
这看起来有点意思
This seems like a good bit of fun.
好吧 过来
Well, come on over.
我们正有个有趣的搏斗呢
We got us a fight goin' on that's a good bit of fun.
你陪我到吧台好吗?
Won't you accompany me to the bar?
白人 在房间里要脱帽 连我都知道的
You don't wear a hat in the house, white man. Even I know that.
- 舒尔茨医生  - 何其荣幸啊
- Dr. Schultz.  - What a rare pleasure.
继续战斗 黑鬼
Keep fighting, niggers.
- 我要补上 是荣誉  - 见到你是我的光荣
- And I might add, an honor.  - Honor to meet you.
请坐 是我的荣幸
Please have a seat, the pleasure's all mine.
自由人姜戈要什么就给他什么
Get free man Django here whatever he wants.
我要甜茶和波旁酒
And I'll have sweet tea and bourbon.
黑鬼 用你的体重优势! 就是这样
Use your weight, boy, use your weight! There you go.
他更高更壮!
He's much bigger and stronger!
快点!
Come on, now!
他不按我说的做 天啊
He's not doing what I told him, for God's sakes.
快一点 黑鬼! 这是生死之争!
Come on, now, boy! It's a fight to the death!
你到底要不要打败他?
You either hit him or are you ain't?
- 大块头弗雷德 加把劲!
- Big Fred, come on!
把他转过来! 马上...
Turn him around! Now...
黑鬼 利用你的优势! 加把劲儿啊! 发挥你的强项!
Use your strength, boy! Come on, now! Use your strength!
就这样!
There you go!
就是这样! 看看
There you go! Look at that.
看吧 我告诉你要更用力
See, I told you to put some more power in there.
按我说的做 黑鬼!
Do what I told you, boy!
就这样!
There you go!
- 不!  - 照我说的来!
- No!  - Do what I told ya!
把他戳瞎 黑鬼! 戳瞎他!
Blind him black, boy! Blind him black!
哦 不 路易吉
Oh, no, Luigi.
哇! 哦 哈哈!
Whoo! Whoo-hoo-hoo!
噢...
Oh...
把他了结
Finish him.
继续啊 了结了他!
Go on, boy, finish him!
这就是他被叫作大块头弗雷德的原因
That's why they call him Big Fred.
- 花的每分钱都值得  - 好吧 路易吉再见
- Worth every penny.  - Well, arrivederci, Luigi.
现在上来吧 休息一下
Come on up, now, boy. Get yourself a rest.
你做的很好 相当好
You did a fine job. A real fine job.
默西迪丝
Mercedes.
我要龙舌兰酒
Tequila.
你叫什么名字?
What's your name?
我叫姜戈
Django.
你能拼写吗?
Can you spell it?
是D-J-A-N-G-O
D-J-A-N-G-O.
D不发音
The D is silent.
我知道了
I know.
莫吉先生 你来照看我的新男仆
Mr. Moguy, want you to take care of my new boy here.
给他找个房间 带软床的
You find him a room with a soft bed,
再找个人好好伺候下他
then you bring him up a pony to lick his pole.
但你明早得准备到糖果农场 听清了吗?
But you be ready to travel to Candyland tomorrow morning, now, ya hear?
听到了 先生坎迪
Yessir, Monsieur Candie.
罗斯科 走之前给弗雷德一大瓶啤酒
Before you go, Roscoe, get Fred here a tall beer.
好好享受 是你自己挣来的
You enjoy that, boy. You've earned it.
是的 先生
Yessir.
- 黑人 你叫什么?  - 他名叫姜戈·弗里曼
- What's your name, boy?  - His name is Django Freeman.
你从哪儿把他挖来的?
Where'd you dig him up?
一个偶然的机缘让我遇上了姜戈
A fortuitous turn of events brought Django and myself together.
我听说过你
I've heard tell about you.
我听说你四处散布说曼丁哥人不太强
I heard you been telling everybody them Mandingos ain't no damn good.
大家卖的根本不值钱
Ain't nothin' nobody is sellin' is worth buyin'.
我好奇... 什么使你成为曼丁哥专家的?
I'm curious... what makes you such a Mandingo expert?
我好奇是什么让你如此好奇
I'm curious what makes you so curious.
- 你说什么 黑鬼?  - 布奇 冷静
- What did you say, boy?  - Calm down, Butch.
他无意...
No offense given...
也没有冒犯
none taken.
先生坎迪...
Monsieur Candie...
如果你能直接询问我的话 就再好不过了
I'd appreciate if you could direct your line of inquiry toward me.
第一...
One...
你还没喝呢 能给你来点提神吗?
you do not have anything to drink. Can I get you a tasty refreshment?
- 好的! 我要啤酒  - 极好的
- Yes! I'll have a beer.  - Wunderbar.
罗斯科 给这位胡子先生一份啤酒
Roscoe, a beer for the man with the beard,
我自己来个波利尼西亚珍珠潜水酒
and I will have a Polynesian Pearl Diver.
罗姆酒尽管放
Do not spare the rum.
医生... 我是老练的奴隶贩
Doc... I am a seasoned slaver.
你嘛 还是个新手
You are, well, you are a neophyte.
我只是想确定 这牛仔是否在占你便宜
I'm simply tryin' to ascertain if this cowboy here is takin' advantage of you.
恕我直言 先生坎迪...
With all due respect, Monsieur Candie...
我不是来寻求你的意见的
I didn't seek you out for your advice.
我找你是要买个格斗黑人
I sought you out to purchase a fighting nigger
市场上买不到的那种
at above top-dollar market price.
我印象中 当你让我作观众时
Now I was under the impression, when you granted me an audience,
就是要讨论业务了
it would be to discuss business.
哎 我们还没讨论生意呢
Well, we weren't talkin' business yet.
我们刚才在讨论我的好奇
We were discussin' my curiosity.
谢谢
Thank you.
罗斯科 可可 去外边玩
Roscoe, Coco, go outside and play.
示巴... 你不用动
Sheba... you stay right there.
我知道你指的不是我
I know you didn't mean me.
- 干杯!  - 敬德国
- Prost!  - German.
根据莫吉说的 如果我和你做生意
Now, according to Moguy, if I do business with you,
就是和你们俩都做生意
I'm doing business with both y'all.
他打量 你掏钱? 是这样的吗?
He does the eyeballin', you the billfold? Is that it?
嗯 别说的那么谄媚 但差不多是的
Well, you don't make it sound too flattering, but more or less, yeah.
嗯
Hm.
那么...
So...
机灵鬼...
Bright Boy...
莫吉说你看过我的非洲货了
Moguy tells me you looked over my African flesh
印象并不太深 是吗?
and you was none too impressed, huh?
不是顶级好货
Not for top dollar.
哦 既然这样 我们也没什么好谈的
Well, then, we got nothin' more to talk about.
看看 你想从我这里买黑人强手
You see, you wanna buy a beat-ass nigger from me,
那些就是我想卖的高手 所以...
those are the beat-ass niggers I wanna sell so...
他不想买你出售的黑人
He don't wanna buy the niggers you wanna sell.
他想买你不想卖的黑人
He wants the nigger you don't wanna sell.
喔 我不出售不想卖的黑鬼
Well, I don't sell the niggers I don't wanna sell.
这个嘛 你不想卖最好的
Well, you won't sell your best.
也不会卖第二好的
You won't even sell your second best.
但第三好的...? 你还是不想卖
But your third best...? You don't want to sell him either.
但如果我出个惊天报价 你不得不考虑一下...
But if I made you an offer so ridiculous you'd be forced to consider it...
谁知道会发生什么呢?
who knows what could happen?
你觉得什么是惊天报价?
And what do you consider ridiculous?
对一个有真正天赋的货色来说 那个对的人?
For a truly talented specimen, the right nigger?
你觉得该出价多少 姜戈?
How much would you say, Django?
一万二美金
Twelve thousand dollars.
先生们 刚才我只对你们好奇
Well, gentlemen, you had my curiosity,
但现在我注意到你们了
but now you have my attention.
维利 维利 停车! 停车 啊!
Willie. Willie. Hold up! Hold up. Ah!
- 先生们早上好  - 舒尔茨医生早上好
- Good morning, gentlemen.  - Good Dr. Schultz.
- 今天真美啊 不是吗?  - 不能更美了
- Beautiful morning, isn't it?  - You couldn't have picked a better one.
请跟我们一起乘维多利亚马车吧
Please, won't you take a ride with us here in the Victoria.
噢 非常感谢
Oh, thank you very much.
你可以把马栓到那边
You can tie your horse up back there.
姜戈
Django.
我与我的骨相学同事们不同的一点就是
Where I part company from many of my phrenologist colleagues
我相信黑鬼能达到超乎聪明 超乎天赋
is I believe there is a level above bright, above talented,
超乎忠诚的水准
above loyal that a nigger can aspire to.
也就是 一个万里挑一的黑鬼
Say, one nigger that just pops up in 10,000.
一个杰出的黑人
The exceptional nigger.
天气不错啊 是不是 机灵鬼?
Bright day, huh, Bright Boy?
太阳升起来了
Sun is up.
照耀我们所有人
Shining on all of us.
- 医生 请坐  - 谢谢
- Have a seat, doc.  - Thank you.
相当荣幸
Quite an honor.
- 荣幸的是我们  - 谢谢
- The honor is all ours.  - Thank you.
但我坚信 一段时间后
But I do believe that, given time,
像机灵鬼这样的杰出黑鬼...
exceptional niggers like Bright Boy here...
会变得不是多...
become if not frequent...
就是更多
more frequent.
机灵鬼 你就是万里挑一
Bright Boy, you are that one in 10,000.
咱们这规矩是跟上 不是赶上 黑鬼
The name of the game is keep up, not catch up, nigger.
哇!
Whoa!
- 碰抢你就死  - 大家都冷静!
- Touch your guns, you die.  - Everybody, calm down!
我目睹了全部过程 没有伤亡
Now I saw the whole thing. No harm done.
你在开玩笑吗?
Are you kidding me?
- 这黑鬼刚刚...  - 我说了没有伤亡!
- This nigger just...  - I said no harm done!
现在把手伸出来 别碰手枪!
Now take your hand off your pistol!
布奇 你也是
Butch, that means you too.
大家别敌对我的客人
Everybody stop antagonizing my guest.
胡特! 起来上马
Hoot! Get back up on your horse.
他把我锁骨弄断了!
He broke my collarbone!
看在上帝份上 大家帮胡特上马吧
For God's sake, somebody please help Hoot here back up on his goddamn horse.
- 是的 老板  - 哦 你还真幸运啊 黑鬼
- Yessir, boss.  - Oh, now you are one lucky nigger.
你最好听你老板的 白人
You better listen to your boss, white boy.
哦 我会伴随月光和你漫步
Oh, I'm gonna go walking in the moonlight with you.
你想牵我的手?
You wanna hold my hand?
威利 带我们回家
Willie, take us home.
前进!
Start moving!
把他们带出去!
Head 'em out!
你眼睛有问题吗 小子?
You got a problem with your eyeball, boy?
先生 没有
No, sir.
你想让我踢你眼睛吗?
You want a boot heel in it?
先生 不是
No, sir.
那就别盯着我
Then you keep your goddamn eyeballs off me.
你再那样对我翻白眼 我就给你个恨我的理由
You flash that bad look at me again, I'll give you a reason not to like me.
黑鬼 快走!
Now move, nigger!
你们这些黑鬼最好看清形势
You niggers are gonna understand something about me.
我比这里的任何白人都坏
I'm worse than any of these white men here.
不想吃苦头 就别盯着我
You get the molasses out your ass, you keep your goddamn eyeballs off me.
他是粗暴的那类 不是吗?
He is a rambunctious sort, ain't he?
的确
Indeed.
我们能停一会儿吗 我要跟我的人说几句话?
May we stop for a moment so I may put a word in my man's ear?
你知道 我希望对糖果农场的货一见钟情
You know, I'm expecting to fall in love once I see the specimens at Candyland,
在那之前 如果我能跟我朋友
so before that moment, it would be good if I could have
开个机密的战略会议就更好了
a confidential strategy meeting with my confidant.
你要告诉我你在做什么吗?
You mind telling me what the hell you doing?
我确定布隆希达就在糖果农场
I confirmed that Broomhilda's at Candyland.
- 你确定是她?  - 他没叫名字
- You're sure it's her?  - He didn't call her by name,
但她是个年轻女性 背上有鞭痕 会说德语
but she's a young lady, whip marks on her back and speaks German.
虽然这样假设不太明智
Now, while it's not wise to assume,
但这种情况下 我想是很可靠的
in this instance, I think it's pretty safe.
还有一点 别这么急着报复
Point being, don't get so carried away with your retribution.
你忘了我们为何而来
You lose sight of why we're here.
- 你觉得我忘了?  - 是的
- You think I lost sight of that?  - Yes, I do.
别再和坎迪对着干
Stop antagonizing Candie.
小心露馅或者更严重 我们俩都会被杀的
You're going to blow this whole charade, or more than likely get us both killed.
而我 还不想死在美国密西西比州的奇克索郡
And I, for one, don't intend to die in Chickasaw County, Mississippi, USA.
我没和他对着干 是想引起他的兴趣
I'm not antagonizing him. I'm intriguing him.
你在冲这些可怜的奴隶们大喊
You're yelling abuse at these poor slaves.
我想起那个当着孩子的面杀死他爸的男人
I recall the man who had me kill another man in front of his son
他可是眼都不眨
and he didn't bat a eye.
记得吗?
You remember that?
当然记得
Yeah, of course I remember.
你当时说 自己的命运自己掌握
What you said was that this is my world,
而要掌握自己的命运 同流合污在所难免
and in my world you gotta get dirty.
我现在就在同流合污
So that's what I'm doing. I'm getting dirty.
和我的原话不完全一样 但...
Well, you're paraphrasing a tad, but...
大意就是这样
that was the general gist.
糖果农场见
See you at Candyland.
好了 黑鬼们 继续走
All right, niggers, back at it.
你也是 月光男
That means you too, Moonlight.
哎呀 是达达尼安!
I'll be. D'Artagnan!
小子 为什么干逃跑这种蠢事?
Now, boy, why do a fool thing like run off?
我没办法再打了 坎迪先生
I can't fight no more, Monsieur Candie.
你可以的
Yes, you can.
你不一定会赢 但你小子很能打
You might not be able to win, but your ass can fight.
斯通塞弗先生 能不能让这些臭狗闭嘴?
Mr. Stonesipher, would you please shut these goddamn dogs up?
- 我都没办法思考了!  - 闭嘴 玛莎!
- I cannot hear myself think!  - Quiet down, Marsha!
玛莎 别叫了! 玛莎!
Marsha, hush up! Marsha!
别叫了! 喂!
Hush up! Hey!
把这些臭狗从这黑鬼身边拉走!
Get these goddamn dogs away from this nigger!
下来吧 小子... 从树上下来吧
Come on now, boy... get on out that tree.
遵命 先生
Yes, sir.
他不见了多久?
How long was he loose?
昨晚 昨天
A night. Day.
前天半夜
Half the other night.
他逃了多远?
How far he get off the property?
出了庄园大概20英里
About 20 miles off the prop.
对于一个瘸子来说 算是逃得很远了
Pretty far considering that limp he got.
莫吉先生 达达尼安这周五会和谁打?
Mr. Moguy, who was D'Artagnan supposed to fight on Friday?
一个新人
One of this new lot.
看他这副死人样 瞎子也不会赌他赢
Well, way he looks now, a blind Indian wouldn't bet a bead on him.
求您了 坎迪先生 我已经没办法再打了
Please, Monsieur Candie, I ain't got it in me no more.
- 别 别 别  - 我不行了...
- Now, now, now, now, now.  - I can't...
别求我
Now, no begging.
别利用我的同情心
No playing on my soft heart.
- 你有麻烦了 小子  - 知道 先生
- You in trouble now, son.  - Yes, sir.
我花500块买了你
I done paid $500 for you.
这500块是要你在被别人打死之前
When I pay $500, then I expect to get five fights out of a nigger
- 打够5场比赛  - 先生
- before he roll over and play dead.  - Sir.
你得明白 我是个生意人
You got to understand that I'm running a business here.
- 你只打了三场  - 但三场我都赢了
- You fought three fights.  - But I won every one.
没错 没错
Yes, you did. Yes, you did.
但最后那场 你差点就输了
But that last one, you muddled the line between winning and losing.
是的 先生
Yes, sir.
板上钉钉的事实是
Still, the fact remains:
我花了500块 你他妈就得给我打够5场!
I pay $500, I want five goddamn fights!
我那500块怎么办?
So what about my $500, huh?
What about my $500?
你来补偿给我?
You gonna reimburse me?
你连"补偿"是什么意思都不知道吧?
You even know what "reimburse" means?
我来补偿你!
I'll reimburse you!
真的?
You will?
真的
Yep.
你要花500块
You'll pay $500
去买一个扫地都不会的独眼龙?
for practically a one-eyed old Joe ain't fit to push a broom?
他不会买的
No, he won't.
他只是不想再看你耍他了
He just tired of you toying with him is all.
事实上 我也不想再看了
Matter of fact, so am I.
但我们不会花一分钱去买这个黑小子
But we ain't paying a penny for that pickaninny.
买了也没用 对吧 医生?
Ain't got no use for him. Ain't that right, doc?
你听到了吧
You heard him.
请原谅斯通塞弗先生的惊讶表情
You're gonna have to excuse Mr.Stonesipher's slack-jawed gaze.
他这辈子都没见过像你这样的黑人
He ain't never seen a nigger like you ever in his life.
没错吧 斯通塞弗先生
Ain't that right, Mr. Stonesipher?
没错
That right.
说实话
For that matter,
我也没见过
nor have I.
既然...
Now...
你们不肯花钱买下这个黑小子
seeing as you won't pay a penny for this pickaninny here,
那你们不介意我用自己的手段处置这个黑鬼吧?
you won't mind me handling this nigger any way I see fit?
他是你的人
He's your nigger.
斯通塞弗先生?
Mr. Stonesipher?
让玛莎和它的伙伴 送达达尼安去黑鬼天堂吧
Let Marsha and her bitches send D'Artagnan to nigger heaven.
玛莎! 玛莎 去咬他!
Marsha! Marsha, hey, get him!
咬他! 咬他!
Get him, get him!
你的老板好像不太喜欢
Your boss looks a little green around the gills
黑鬼搏击这种血腥的运动
for a blood sport like nigger fighting.
不 他只是没见过一个被狗撕成碎片的人
Nah, he just ain't used to seeing a man ripped apart by dogs is all.
但你经常见到?
You are used to it?
我只是对美国人的所做所为习以为常
I'm just a little more used to Americans than he is.
先生坎迪...
Now, Monsieur Candie...
我们随时可以继续走
whenever you're ready.
我们骑了五个小时马 就为了看看你的私人珍藏
We rode five hours so you could show off your stock.
别让我们失望
Let's get to it.
如果你的人是这副模样 我可不太满意
Cause as of now, if he's an example, I ain't impressed.
跟我来
Follow me.
密西西比银行
卡尔文·坎迪
让他们在左边排好队
Line them up to the left here now, boy.
抬头挺胸!
Stand up straight, now!
过去
Get up there.
过去 快点
Get up there, boy. Come on.
排好队! 排好队!
Give me a line! Give me a line!
排好队! 站直了!
Get in line there! Straighten up!
你好! 我的史蒂芬!
Hello! Stephen, my boy!
好好好 你好 臭小子
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Hello, my ass.
那个骑着马的黑鬼是谁?
Who this nigger up on that nag?
史蒂芬 你早饭吃了炸药吗? 怎么这么暴躁?
Stephen, you have nails for breakfast? What's the matter? Why you so ornery?
- 你惦记着我吗?  - 我可惦记你了 先生
- You miss me, huh?  - Oh, yes, sir.
就像猪惦记泔水一样!
I miss you like a hog miss slop!
就像婴儿惦记妈妈的乳头一样
Like a baby miss mammy's titty.
我像惦记鞋里的石子那样惦记着你
I miss you like I misses a rock in my shoe.
我得问你 那个骑着马的黑鬼是谁?
Now, I axed you: Who this nigger on that nag?
喂 雪球
Hey, Snowball.
想知道我或者我的马的名字 问我就行
Wanna know my name or the name of my horse, you ask me.
你叫谁"雪球"呢 小子?
Just who the hell you calling "Snowball," horse boy?
我要把你这黑鬼从马上拖下来
I'll snatch your black ass off that nag there
扔到泥地里 我的动作能快到...
and in the mud so fast...
- 让你晕头转向  - 史蒂芬 史蒂芬 史蒂芬
- make your head spin.  - Stephen, Stephen, Stephen.
别激动 姜戈是自由身
Let's keep it funny. Django here's a free man.
- 这个黑鬼?  - 那个黑鬼
- This nigger here?  - That nigger there.
我来介绍你们认识
Let me at least introduce the two of you.
姜戈 这是一个和你一样不要脸的黑鬼 史蒂芬
Django, this is another cheeky black bugger like yourself, Stephen.
史蒂芬 这位是姜戈 你们之间肯定有仇
Stephen, this here's Django. You two oughta hate each other.
卡尔文 你还怕这黑鬼不高兴? 他是何方神圣?
Calvin, just who the hell is this nigger you feels the need to entertain?
姜戈和这位穿灰西装的舒尔茨医生 是我的顾客
Django and his friend in gray here, Dr. Schultz, are customers.
是我们的客人 史蒂芬
And they are our guests, Stephen.
你这个老东西得对他们客气点
And you, you old decrepit bastard, oughta show them every hospitality.
- 知道吗?  - 知道 先生 那个白人我能理解
- You understand that?  - Yes, sir. Him I understand.
但我不明白为什么要对这个黑鬼客气
But I don't know why I got to take lip off this nigger.
你不需要明白 懂我的意思?
You don't have to know why. Do you understand?
是的 先生 懂了
Yes, sir. I understand.
很好 他们会在这里过夜
Well, good. They're spending the night.
去楼上准备好两间客房
Go up in the guest bedrooms and get two ready.
他要住在大宅里?
He gonna stay in The Big House?
史蒂芬 他是个奴隶商人 和其他黑鬼不一样
Stephen, he's a slaver. It's different.
- 住大宅里?  - 你有意见吗?
- In The Big House?  - Well, you got a problem with that?
不 我没意见
Oh, no. I ain't got no problem with it,
如果你不介意烧掉这黑鬼用过的
if you ain't got no problem with burning the bed, the sheets,
床 被单 枕头套之类的东西!
the pillowcases, everything else when this black-ass motherfucker's gone!
这是我来操心的问题! 烧不烧由我!
That is my problem! They are mine to burn!
而你现在的问题是 你没给客人留下好印象!
Now your problem right now is making a good impression!
我命令你立刻解决这个问题
And I want you to start solving that problem right now
并把房间准备好!
and get them goddamn rooms ready!
遵命 坎迪先生
Yes, sir, Monsieur Candie.
快去
Go on, now.
居然让一个黑鬼住在大宅里 不可思议
Can't believe you brought a nigger to stay in The Big House.
你爸肯定会气得从坟墓里跳出来
Your daddy rolling over in his goddamned grave.
瞧他那张破嘴 越来越离谱了
Man, the lip on him. Whoo! He's getting worse and worse.
好了...
Now...
我美若天仙的妹妹在哪里?!
Where is my beautiful sister?!
在那里!
There she is!
舒尔茨医生 这位来自南方的绝色美人是舍妹 她是寡妇
Dr. Schultz, this attractive Southern belle is my widowed sister.
亲爱的 你真是秀色可餐
Darling, you are a tonic for tired eyes.
请允许我向你们介绍 劳拉·李·坎迪·斐茨威利
May I present to you Lara Lee Candie-Fitzwilly.
切斯特 罗德尼 小鸡查理 你们给我滚到鸡圈去
Chester, Rodney, Chicken Charly. Y'all get your ass over by that pen.
- 快 查理 快点!  - 快走
- Come on, Charly. Come on, now!  - Let's go.
你们知道鸡圈在哪里
You know where it is.
跑快点!
Like you on a rope!
黑鬼不许走路 只许跑步!
Niggers don't walk around here, niggers run!
先生坎迪?
Monsieur Candie?
话说你刚才提到了一个黑妞?
Yeah. About that matter about the nigger girl you were talking about?
黑妞?
Nigger gal?
是的 我记得你说她会说德语
Yeah, I believe you mentioned she spoke German.
是的! 希尔迪 你对她有兴趣?
Ah, yes! Hildi, what about her?
在参观你的奴隶之前 能先把她送到我的房间吗?
Do you think before the demonstration, you could send her around to my room?
你这个老滑头 举手之劳
You little dickens, you. I don't see why not.
史蒂芬 你安顿好他们后 叫希尔迪过来
Stephen, when you get through showing them to their rooms, go fetch Hildi,
把她打扮得漂漂亮亮的
get her cleaned up and smelling real nice,
然后送到舒尔茨医生的房间
and sent over to Dr. Schultz's room here.
事实上 坎迪先生
Actually, Monsieur Candie, sir,
有件事我还没告诉你
there's something I ain't told you about yet.
- 什么事?  - 希尔迪在热箱里
- What?  - Uh, Hildi in the hot box.
她为什么会在那里?
What's she doing there?
你说被关在热箱是为什么?
What you think she doing there in the hot box?
她在受罚
She's being punished.
- 她犯了什么事?  - 她又逃跑了
- What she do?  - She run off again.
天啊 史蒂芬 我不在家的时候跑了几个人?
Jesus Christ, Stephen, how many people ran away while I was gone?
- 两个  - 她什么时候逃跑的?
- Two.  - When did she go?
昨晚 今天早上被抓回来了
Last night. They brung her back this morning.
她没被斯通塞弗的狗撕成碎片吧?
How bad did Stonesipher's dogs tear her up?
她很走运 那些狗当时在追达达尼安
Lucky for her, they was out chasing D'Artagnan's ass.
是比利和科迪找到她并抓她回来的
Bill and Cody went looking for her, found her, brung her back.
她受了点伤 但都是她穿过灌木丛的时候
Now, she a little beat-up. But she done that to her own damn self
自己弄伤的
running through them damn bushes and shit.
她被关多久了?
How long she been in the box?
还能关多久? 一整天
How long you think she been in there? All damn day.
还得再关十天
And the little bitch got ten more days to be in there.
- 算了 放她出来吧  - 放她出来? 为什么?
- Still, take her out.  - Take her out? Why?
因为我说要放她出来 舒尔茨医生是我的客人
Because I said so, that's why. Dr. Schultz is my guest.
希尔迪是我的奴隶
Hildi is my nigger.
我们南方人对客人有求必应
Southern hospitality dictates I make her available to him.
- 可是 坎迪先生 她逃跑了  - 天啊 史蒂芬
- But, Monsieur Candie, she run off.  - Jesus Christ, Stephen.
会德语的黑鬼就是用来服侍德国客人的
What is the point of having a nigger that speaks German
如果这都做不到 那要他们有何用?
if you can't wheel them out when you have a German guest?
我知道这不太方便 但你还是放这小妞出来吧
Now, I realize it is inconvenient, but still, you take her ass out.
遵命 先生
Yes, sir.
劳拉·李! 你和科拉负责
Lara Lee! Will you and Cora be responsible
帮希尔迪梳妆打扮吧
for getting Hildi cleaned up and presentable for Dr. Schultz here.
没问题 亲爱的
Of course, darling.
先生们 很抱歉 走了这么长的路 鄙人已经很累了
Now, gentlemen, I do apologize, but I am weary from our travels beyond words.
请允许我稍作休息
It is time for me to rest my tired eyes.
听到主人说的话没有! 把这贱人放出来!
Y'all done heard the man! Get her ass up outta there!
科拉! 过来!
Cora! Come here!
带她去那边梳妆打扮 然后把她带回来给这位...
Get over there and get her cleaned up, bring her back over here to Dr...
- 你叫什么来着? 舒茨?  - 舒尔茨
- What he say your name is? Shoots?  - Schultz.
舒尔茨医生 把她带过来 快点
Schultz. Get her back over here. Hurry up, girl.
遵命
Yes, sir.
小妞 站起来
Come on, girl. Stand up.
你是想跟我来还是想住那个小盒子?
Is you coming with me or is you gonna sleep in that little box over yonder?
你们好
Hello, ladies.
舒尔茨医生 请允许我向您介绍布隆希达
Dr. Schultz. May I introduce to you Broomhilda?
希尔迪 这位是舒尔茨医生
Hildi, this is Dr. Schultz.
很高兴认识你 布隆希达
It's a pleasure to meet you, Broomhilda.
你的主人对你赞不绝口
I've heard a lot of good things about you.
您也知道 不是每个黑鬼都会说德语的
Well, it's not every nigger speaks German, don't ya know.
看着你 布隆希达
As I look at you now, Broomhilda,
我感受得到 所有因你而生的激情都是完全合理的
I can see all the passions you inspire are completely justified.
这位医生是德国人
The doctor here speaks German.
听说你也会讲德语?
And I've been informed you do as well?
来吧 说两句德语来听听
Go ahead, girl. Speak a little German.
很荣幸能用德语与您交谈
棒极了
Astonishing.
请进吧 小姑娘
- 我再给您拿点...  - 非常感谢
- And I shall bring you...  - Much obliged.
我给你倒杯水好吗?
好的
Ja.
别害怕
Don't be afraid.
失陪一下
我知道你很久没说德语了
所以我会说慢点
我跟你说德语只是为了不让坎迪的人偷听到我们的谈话
抱歉
Hm. Pardon.
你真漂亮
谢谢夸奖
Danke.
我有位朋友 他也是你朋友
我们大费周章
千里迢迢
来找你 小姑娘
来救你
喝吧
我和他打算
救你离开这个虎穴
我没有朋友
你有
谁?
我不能告诉你
我们的朋友很有演员天赋
这位朋友在哪里?
就在那扇门后站着
你得保证不会尖叫?
向我保证
我保证
好啊 小鬼头
Hey, little trouble maker.
你小子口才不错啊
You silver-tongued devil, you.
- 你们快点  - 这些已经准备好了 科拉小姐
- Hurry up, girl.  - These ready, Miss Cora.
不不不 他们晚上要喝酒
No, no, no, they drinking tonight.
到楼下去 把坎迪先生喜欢喝的那罐红酒拿上来 听到了吗?
Go downstairs, get the big jug with the red stuff Monsieur Candie like, hear?
- 你那漂亮的大屁股挡着我的道了  - 别说你不喜欢我的大屁股
- Get your big pretty ass out the way.  - You know you like it.
那是因为你知道我喜欢什么
That's cause you knows what I like.
快点继续做饼干
Ooh! Come on with these biscuits, girl.
先生坎迪 毋庸置疑 他们都是好货色
Look, Monsieur Candie, they were all fine specimens, no doubt about it.
但很明显 最好的三个是山姆森...
But the best three by far were Samson...
- 还有一个叫什么?  - 高迪
- What's that other one's name?  - Goldie.
高迪 还有爱斯基摩·乔
Goldie. And Eskimo Joe.
顺便问一句 他为什么叫爱斯基摩·乔?
By the way, why is he called Eskimo Joe?
天知道那些黑鬼的绰号是怎么来的
You never know how these nigger nicknames get started.
他本名叫乔 也许他总是觉得冷吧?
His name was Joe, maybe one day he said he was cold. Who knows?
无论如何 山姆森是最好的那个 我们都知道
Well, regardless, Samson's your best. We all know that.
你肯定不卖他 我也知道为什么 因为他是顶级的
You will never sell him, and I can see why. He's a champion.
不 他们三个都是顶级的
Hm-hm. All three are champions.
只有山姆森是顶级的
Samson's the champion.
其他两个只是很出色而已
Them other two pretty good.
卡尔文 这个黑鬼竟敢顶嘴...
Calvin, now what's this nigger you let...
没事
It's all right.
有件事你得明白 先生坎迪
You have to understand, Monsieur Candie,
我承认 关于黑鬼搏击游戏我还是新手
while admittedly a neophyte in the nigger fight game,
但我之前在欧洲巡演马戏团待过一阵子
I do have a little bit of a background in the European traveling circus.
是吗?
Is that right?
所以说 只要涉及到表演 我就有发言权
Hence, I have big ideas when it comes to presentation.
我要的不止是一个大块头
I need something more than just a big nigger.
他还得有架势
Yeah, he needs to have panache.
- 得有什么?  - 架势 是...
- Need to have what? What?  - Panache. Uh...
- 知道怎么表现自己  - 表现力 对
- A sense of Showmanship.  - Showmanship, yes.
我要把他称为黑人大力神
I want to be able to bill him as The Black Hercules.
黑人大力神 这都被你想到了?
The Black Hercules, isn't that clever?
黑鬼大力神还差不多
More like Nigger-les.
我说过 "我愿意花最高价
I said, and I quote: "I would pay top dollar for
买'合适的黑鬼'"
'the right nigger'."
我意思不是说爱斯基摩·乔不合适
Now I'm not saying that Eskimo Joe is the wrong nigger, per se.
但他真的无可挑剔吗?
But is he right as rain?
舒尔茨医生
Oh, Dr. Schultz,
你得知道 在黑鬼搏击游戏中
I will have you know there is no one in the nigger fight game
最看重表现力的人
that appreciates the value of showmanship
非鄙人卡尔文·坎迪莫属
more than Monsieur Calvin J. Candie here.
非我主人莫属
Nobody.
但我们不能忘了黑鬼搏击游戏中
But one must not forget the most important thing
最重要的一点
in the nigger fight game.
他必须能打赢比赛
And that is a nigger that can win fights.
你首要考虑的是赢 接着考虑的还是赢 赢赢赢
Now that should be your first, second, third, fourth, and fifth concern.
你要先确定他能打赢
Now, after you have that, and you know you have that,
再去加这些噱头
then you can start to implement a grand design.
换句话说 打赢才是硬道理
In other words, first thing is first.
打赢才是硬道理
First thing's first.
你们很合得来嘛
Ooh! I see you two getting on.
非常合得来
Famously.
坎迪先生 我已经四年没听到过母语了
Oh, Monsieur Candie, you can't imagine what it's like
你无法想像这有多么难受
not to hear your native tongue in four years.
在波士顿(美国北方城市)待两个星期我都受不了
Well, hell, I can't imagine two weeks in Boston.
在波士顿待两个星期!
Two weeks in Boston!
坎迪先生 你真幽默!
Monsieur Candie, you a mess!
在波士顿待两个星期!
Two weeks in Boston!
能用母语交谈真开心
I can't express the joy I felt conversing in my mother tongue.
希尔迪又是个口齿伶俐的姑娘
And Hildi is a charming conversation companion.
当心点 舒尔茨医生
Well, be careful now, Dr. Schultz.
当心自己爱上一个黑妞了
You might-a caught yourself a little dose of nigger love.
这种感情可是相当厉害
Nigger love's a powerful emotion, boy.
就像一池子黑焦油
It's like a pool of black tar.
陷进去就出不来了
Once it catches your ass, you're caught.
没错 先生 无法自拔
Yes, sir, you stuck.
不知道呢 医生
I don't know, doctor.
你可以用德语对她说各种各样的甜言蜜语
You can lay on all the German sweet talk you want,
但这小妞貌似对姜戈很有兴趣
but it looks like this pony's got big eyes for Django.
这是本能反应
Well, naturally.
能吸引她注意力的只有飞翔的雄鹰
It is the soaring eagle that attracts her attention,
而不是被拔光毛的鸡
not the plucked chicken.
舒尔茨医生 不需如此自贬
Dr. Schultz, don't be so down on yourself.
你可是一名有为的欧洲绅士
You are quite the dapper European gentleman.
要把盘子洗干净
You got to clean these dishes,
就得用胳膊肘去洗 听见了吗?
you got to put your elbow in these dishes, you hear me?
你认识那个黑鬼吧?
You know that nigger, don't you?
- 哪个?  - "哪个?"
- Who?  - "Who?"
别跟我装傻 小贱人 你知道我说的是哪个
Don't "who" me, bitch. You know who I'm talking about.
坐在餐桌上那个?
At the table?
我不认识他
I don't know him.
- 你不认识他  - 不认识
- You don't know him.  - No.
- 礼貌点  - 不认识 先生
- "No," what?  - No, sir.
你不会跟我撒谎吧?
You wouldn't lie to me, now, would you?
好
OK.
这是你说的
Yeah. If you say so.
毋庸置疑 爱斯基摩·乔符合我们的要求
Eskimo Joe's a quality nigger, no doubt about it.
但如果是我来付钱 我不会花12000块去买他
But if it was my money, I wouldn't pay no $12,000 for him.
你会花多少钱?
What would your price be?
如果我出手阔绰的话
Well, if I was inclined to be generous,
我不知道他为何值得我出大价钱...
and I don't know why I would be inclined to be generous...
也许会出九千吧
9,000. Maybe.
舒尔茨医生 我还是重申一下这次谈判的由来吧
Dr. Schultz, let me reclarify how this whole negotiation came about.
要知道 并不是我找上你们要卖黑奴的
You see, it wasn't me who came to you to sell a nigger.
确实不是
Sure wasn't.
是你主动来找我 说要买黑奴的
It was you who approached me to buy one.
- 的确如此  - 机灵鬼提出的
- Sure was.  - Now, that $9,000 figure
九千美元这个数字也还算公道
Bright Boy's been bandyin' about, that ain't too far off from right.
但如果我想以这个价钱卖了爱斯基摩·乔
And if I wanted to sell Eskimo Joe for that,
- 那随时都可以卖出去  - 随时都行
- I could do so any day of the week.  - Any day.
但就如你在格林维尔所说的 医生... 我不想卖他
But, like you said in Greenville, doctor... I don't want to sell him.
只不过是你出的一万两千美元的好价钱
It was only your ridiculous offer of $12,000
- 才让我予以考虑的  - 没错
- that made me even consider it.  - Hm-mm.
要知道 先生坎迪 您这话的确很有说服力
You know, Monsieur Candie, you do possess the power of persuasion.
好吧 先生坎迪 成交
Why not? Monsieur Candie, you have a deal.
- 一万二 买爱斯基摩·乔  - 万岁 医生
- Eskimo Joe, $12,000.  - Hooray, doctor.
万岁 真是明智的决断
Hooray. And a wise decision that is.
然而 这是很大一笔巨款
However, that is a tremendous amount of money.
就像你有莫吉先生一样 我也有律师
And the way you have your Mr. Moguy, I have a lawyer.
一个叫塔托的挑剔鬼
Persnickety man named Tuttle.
所以在我安心与你一手交钱一手交货之前
And I would need my Mr. Tuttle to draw up a legal contract
我得让塔托先生起草一份合法的合同
before I'd feel comfortable exchanging that amount of money for flesh.
可以
Hm-mm.
当然还得让我指定的医师
Not to mention having Eskimo Joe examined
- 给爱斯基摩·乔做个检查  - 这是自然
- by a physician of my choosing.  - Naturally.
这样一来 我大概...
So, say I return in about...
- 五天后回来  - 五天?
- five days time.  - Five days?
和T塔托先生一起过来
With my Mr. Tuttle.
然后就让我的塔托先生和你的莫吉先生
And then my Mr. Tuttle and your Mr. Moguy
两个人把最后的细节都敲定
can hash out the finer details between themselves.
我说这真是太棒了 医生 棒极了
I say splendid, doctor. Splendid.
先生们...
Gentlemen...
我们来干一杯
may I propose a toast.
敬爱斯基摩·乔 也许现在该称他为黑人大力神了吧?
To Eskimo Joe. Or shall we call him The Black Hercules?
敬黑人大力神
To The Black Hercules.
The Black Hercules.
敬黑人大力神
To The Black Hercules.
您说得对 医生 这名字的确响亮
You was right, doctor. That name do have pan-ass.
真不错
Hm.
希尔迪 给我满上
Hildi, top my drink off.
希尔迪 你喜欢在大宅子的晚宴上当侍从吗?
So, Hildi, how you like servin' at the big table in The Big House, huh?
坎迪先生问你话呢 快点回答
When Monsieur Candie talk to you, you answers.
- 我很喜欢 坎迪先生  - 是吧
- I like it a lot, Monsieur Candie.  - Hm-mm.
总好过在热箱子里关着 或是在布满荆棘的
It's a lot better than sizzlin' in that Hot Box or draggin' your ass
灌木丛里奔跑
through a bramble bush.
但也许却不如取悦那些曼丁哥来得有趣
But maybe it's not quite as much fun as gettin' to pleasure all them Mandingos,
- 对吧 甜心?  - 天啊 她喜欢那些黑鬼
- huh, sugar bear?  - Oh, Lord, she like them niggers.
- 的确如此  - 山姆森那种? 喜欢吗?
- Sure do.  - Like Samson? Huh?
不喜欢 先生
No, sir.
要知道 坎迪先生
You know, Monsieur Candie,
医生看到希尔迪伤痕累累的后背时 可能很感兴趣
the doctor here might be interested in seein' Hildi's peeled back,
因为他们德国没有什么黑奴
seein' as how they don't have many niggers where he come from.
舒尔茨医生 你和希尔迪独处的时候
Dr. Schultz, when you was alone with Hildi, here,
就说说德语呢 还是脱了她的衣服?
did you just speak German or did you get to take her clothes off?
不 我们只是聊了聊...
No, we just talked and...
所以你没看过她的背?
Oh, so you haven't seen her back?
- 没有...  - 不 这不对
- I haven't...  - No, no, no, no.
史蒂芬说得对 你也许会觉得这个很有趣
Stephen's right, you might find this interesting.
希尔迪 快点 把衣服脱了 让舒尔茨医生看看你的背
Hildi, go on, take off your dress. Show Dr. Schultz your back here.
- 快点  - 呃 卡尔文
- Go on.  - Uh, Calvin.
我可是才把她收拾妥当 打扮漂亮的
I just got her all dressed up and lookin' nice.
劳拉·李 可舒尔茨医生是从杜塞尔多夫来的
But, Lara Lee, Dr. Schultz is from Dusseldorf.
他们那儿可没有黑奴 他是个医生
They don't got niggers there. He is a man of medicine.
我想黑人对疼痛的忍耐力肯定会让他惊奇的
I'm sure it would fascinate him, the niggers' endurance for pain.
毫无疑问 舒尔茨医生 这些黑奴坚强着呢
These niggers are tough, Dr. Schultz, no doubt about it.
希尔迪背上有四道鞭痕
Hildi's got somethin' like four lashes on her back.
要是劳拉·李被抽上一鞭 肯定早就晕过去了
Lara Lee just get one, she'd lose her goddamn mind.
- 确实如此  - 看看 医生
- Sure would.  - Look at that, doctor.
- 看看 就像一幅画一样  - 卡尔文!
- It's like a paintin'. Look at that.  - Calvin!
我们还在吃饭呢 而且也没人想看她的背
We are eating. Ain't no one wanna look at her whipped up back.
好 好吧 不看了
Fine. Fine, fine, fine, fine.
留到晚饭后 史蒂芬 晚饭后再看
After dinner, then, Stephen. After dinner.
先生 喝酒的时候再看 如何?
During the brandies, gentlemen, hm?
科拉 把这姑娘带下去!
Cora, come get this girl!
- 她被弄得一团糟  - 是 夫人 噢!
- She a mess.  - Yes, ma'am. Oh!
你的衣服怎么解开了? 我才给你穿好的
Why are you all undone? I just got you done up.
跟我过来
Come on in here.
你真是惹到史蒂芬了 你得顺他的意
Baby, you on Stephen bad side, and you need to be on his blind side.
你说你不认识他
You say you ain't know him.
什么?
Huh?
我是说 你刚才说你不认识他
I said, you said you ain't know him.
- 不认识  - 不 你认识
- I don't.  - Yes, you do.
史蒂芬先生...
Mr. Stephen...
我不认识他
I don't.
你为什么要对我撒谎?
Why is you lying to me?
我没有
I ain't.
那你为什么哭?
Then why is you crying?
你吓到我了?
You scarin' me.
- 我怎么吓到你了?  - 因为你这样很恐怖
- Why is I'm scaring you?  - Because you scary.
今天下午和希尔迪说德语
To speak German this afternoon with Hildi
真是让我满心欢喜
was positively soul-enriching.
医生 您这话让我受宠若惊
Doctor, that warms my heart to hear that.
你待在这儿
You stay right here.
您之前说 您愿意卖掉希尔迪
You indicated earlier you'd be willing to part with Hildi.
没错 我的确这么说过
Why, yes. Yessiree bob, I did.
这样的话 允许我再说个提议
In that case, allow me to propose another proposition.
洗耳恭听
I'm all ears.
快点 真该死!
Hurry up, goddamn it!
- 先生坎迪...  - 史蒂芬!
- Monsieur Candie...  - Stephen!
你打断了舒尔茨医生说话
You just interrupted Dr. Schultz here.
很抱歉 舒尔茨医生
I'm sorry, Dr. Schultz.
我的耳朵最近越来越不好使了
My ears ain't worth a damn these days.
请原谅他
Excuse him.
坎迪先生 您可否到厨房 我跟你说几句话?
Monsieur Candie, could I get a word with you in the kitchen?
你是说让我离开我的椅子?
You mean get up out of my chair?
- 希望您能来一趟  - 为什么?
- If'n you could manage it.  - Why?
- 是甜品的事  - 甜品怎么了?
- It's about dessert.  - What about dessert?
我想私下和您说
I'd rather discuss that in private.
我们要吃清蛋糕!
We're having white cake!
后厨还能发生什么闹剧呢?
What sort of melodrama could be brewing back there?
您说得对 先生坎迪 我自己解决
You right, Monsieur Candie. You right. I'll handle it myself.
我在书房等你
Meet me in the library.
我就是不明白您为什么不愿到后厨和那些黑人谈谈
I just can't understand why you won't come talk to these niggers.
要是事情出了什么岔子 您可别怨我
Shit get fucked up around here, you blame me.
好吧! 好吧 亲爱的史蒂芬 我马上就过去
Fine! Fine. Friend Stephen, I will be along momentarily.
好的 先生
Yes, sir.
好吧 先生们 你们也看到了
Well, gentlemen, as you can see,
虽然毫无疑问 他们做菜很棒
talented as they are, no doubt, in the kitchen,
但偶尔还是需要家长来监管一下
from time to time, adult supervision is required.
请恕我失陪片刻
If you'll excuse me a moment.
你们可以去收盘子了
You may clear the dinner service.
都听到了 快点! 快点 姑娘们
You heard him. Go on! Get! Hurry up, girl.
舒尔茨医生 您跟我们说说马戏团的故事吧
So, Dr. Schultz, why don't you regale us with a tale of the circus.
马戏团?
The circus?
怎么了?
What is the matter?
那俩家伙根本不是来买曼丁哥人的
Them motherfuckers ain't here to buy no Mandingos.
他们想要的是那女孩
They wants that girl.
史蒂芬 你到底在说什么呢? 嗯?
Stephen, what the hell are you talking about? Hm?
我是说 他们就是在把您当傻子耍
They playing your ass for a fool is what I'm talking about.
他们根本不是来买强壮的黑奴
They ain't here for no musclebound Jimmie.
他们是来找那女孩的
They here for that girl.
哪... 哪个女孩? 希尔迪吗?
Wh... what girl? Hildi?
没错 就是希尔迪 她和姜戈相互都认识
Yeah, Hildi. Her and Django, them niggers know each other.
他刚买了爱斯基摩·乔
He just bought Eskimo Joe.
- 他付钱给您了吗?  - 不! 还没有 但...
- Did he give you any money?  - No! Not yet. But...
那到目前为止 他还什么都没买
Then he ain't bought diddly. Not yet, nohow.
若不是刚才我打断他
But he's just about to buy
他差点就要把那女孩买到手了
who he come here to buy when I interrupted him.
不用谢我
"Thank you, Stephen." You're welcome, Calvin.
你是怎么想出来的?
Where you gettin' all this?
他们干嘛要大费周章 只是为了买下一个
Why would they go through all that trouble for a nigger
背上有鞭伤 连300美金都不值的黑奴?
with a chewed up back, ain't worth $300?
他们这么做是因为姜戈爱着希尔迪
They doin' it 'cause that nigger Django's in love with Hildi.
她可能就是他老婆
She probably his wife.
至于那个德国佬干嘛要帮这个黑鬼情圣
Now, why that German gives a fuck who that uppity son of a bitch
我肯定就不知道了
is in love with, I'm sure I don't know.
如果她才是他们想买的...
If she's who they want...
干嘛还要绕弯子 扮成来买曼丁哥人呢?
why this whole snake oil pitch about Mandingos, then?
您根本不会在乎区区300美金
You wouldn't pay no never mind to no $300.
但要是一万两千美金呢? 你一定不想错过这笔生意 是吧?
But that 12,000? That made you real friendly, now, didn't it?
的确如此
Yes, it did.
他老婆是吧?
His wife, huh?
如果那是一条蛇 我早就被咬了
If it had been a snake, it would have bit me.
那两个满嘴谎言...
Those lying...
浪费我时间的混蛋
goddamn time-wastin' sons of bitches.
该死的混蛋!
Sons of bitches!
我离开了新奥尔良 所以才能去很多剧院看演出
Out of New Orleans, so I have quite a bit of practice with theater types.
噢 你终于回来了
Oh, there you are.
我都开始以为你和那个老乌鸦一起逃跑了呢
I was beginning to think that you and that old crow run off together.
那会是个噩耗 对吧?
That'd be a hell of a note, wouldn't it?
劳拉·李 我刚往大窗户那儿看了一眼
Lara Lee, I was just looking out the big window.
比利·克劳什在外面打发几个来卖
Billy Crash is out there dealing with some shady slaver
一群小马驹的黑奴
trying to sell a passel of ponies.
你能好心地替我出去看着他们吗? 可以吗?
Would you be a dear, go out there and give them gals an eyeball? Hm?
- 当然可以 哥哥  - 谢谢 亲爱的
- Of course, brother.  - Thank you, darling.
- 没错 生意就没有停歇的时候  - 的确
- Yeah. Business never sleeps.  - Hm-mm.
话说回来 在您离开前
Apropos, before your exit,
我们正讨论到 我是否能买下布隆希达的问题
we were discussing the possibility of my purchasing Broomhilda.
对 没错 医生
Ah, yes. Yes, we were, doctor.
我们稍后再接着谈
And we will again. In a moment.
这位是谁?
Who's your little friend?
这是本
This is Ben.
他是很久以前住在这儿的一个老黑鬼
He's a old Joe that lived around here for a long time.
我是说很久很久以前
And I do mean a long damn time.
老本在这儿照顾我爸爸...
Old Ben here took care of my daddy...
还有我爷爷
and my daddy's daddy.
等有一天我爸爸死了之后...
Till he up and keeled over one day...
老本就开始照顾我
Old Ben took care of me.
身为密西西比州大农场主的儿子
Growing up the son of a huge plantation owner in Mississippi
能让一个白人 接触到许多黑鬼
puts a white man in contact with a whole lotta black faces.
我的一生都在这里度过 就在糖果农场...
I spent my whole life here, right here in Candyland...
身边都是黑鬼
surrounded by black faces.
每天看着他们忙进忙出
Now, seeing them every day, day in, day out,
我只有一个问题:
I only had one question:
他们干嘛不杀了我们?
Why don't they kill us?
就在那个回廊 一连五十年 每周三次
Now, right out there on that porch, three times a week for 50 years,
老本都会用一把剃刀给我爸爸刮胡子
Old Ben here would shave my daddy with a straight razor.
如果我是老本 肯定会用剃刀划开我爸的喉咙
Now, if I was Old Ben, I woulda cut my daddy's goddamn throat
然后就不用花五十年给他当牛做马了
and it wouldn't have taken me no 50 years to do it, neither.
但他没有
But he never did.
为什么?
Why not?
要知道 颅相学
You see, the science of phrenology
是理解两个人种区别的关键
is crucial to understanding the separation of our two species.
看非洲人的头骨
In the skull of the African here,
管辖服从命令的区域
the area associated with submissiveness
比地球上任何其他人种的都要大
is larger than any human or any other subhuman species on planet Earth.
如果你检查一下...
If you examine...
这块头骨...
this piece of skull here...
会看到上面有三个明显的凹陷
you will notice three distinct dimples.
这儿 这儿 还有这儿
Here, here and here.
现在...
Now...
如果我拿着的是艾萨克·牛顿或是伽利略的头骨
if I was holding the skull of an Isaac Newton or Galileo,
那么这三个凹陷应该会出现在
these three dimples would be found in the area of the skull
管辖创造力的... 区域
most associated with... creativity.
但这是老本的头骨
But this is the skull of Old Ben.
而在他的头骨上
And in the skull of Old Ben,
这三个凹陷处
unburdened by genius,
并非在和天才一样的区域 而是在管辖...
these three dimples exist in the area of the skull most associated with...
奴性的地方
servility.
机灵鬼...
Now, Bright Boy...
我承认你很聪明
I will admit you are pretty clever.
但如果我拿这把榔头...
But if I took this hammer here...
砸开你的头骨...
and I bashed in your skull with it...
你会发现你的三个凹陷 就在和老本头骨...
you would have the same three dimples in the same place...
同样的位置
as Old Ben.
嘿! 把手放在桌上!
Hey! Now lay your palms flat on that tabletop!
如果你们的手离开了桌面
If you lift those palms off that turtle shell tabletop,
普奇先生就会开枪 把你们射成马蜂窝
Mr. Pooch is gonna let loose with both barrels of that sawed-off.
虽然今晚在这餐桌上大家说的没几句真话
There have been a lot of lies said around this dinner table here tonight,
但这句是真的!
but that you can believe!
莫吉先生 能劳驾你帮忙把他们皮带上的枪
Mr. Moguy, would you be so kind as to collect the pistol
都收起来吗?
hanging off these boys' hips here?
- 非常感谢  - 医生
- Thank you ever so much.  - Doctor.
我们说到哪儿了?
Where were we?
傻瓜
Jackass.
对了
Ah, yes.
我想你刚才正想跟我提议
I do believe you were just getting ready to make me
要买下布隆希达
a proposition to buy Broomhilda.
我没说错吧?
Am I right?
没错
Right.
把希尔迪带过来!
Bring out Hildi!
站到那边去
Get over there yonder.
坐到椅子上...
Sit your ass in that goddamn...
把双手放在桌上
Lay your hand flat on that tabletop.
然后闭嘴!
Now shut your mouth!
舒尔茨医生 在格林维尔
Dr. Schultz, in Greenville,
你自己说 只要是你相中的黑奴
you yourself said that for the right nigger
你愿意支付其他人认为荒谬的天价
you'd be willin' to pay what some may consider is a ridiculous amount.
我的回答是"您所说的天价是多少?"
To which me myself said, "What is your definition of ridiculous?"
你回答说"一万两千美元"
To which you said, "$12,000."
想你们俩
Now, considering y'all
不远万里骑马过来
have ridden a whole lot of miles,
费尽周折 为了要买这位姑娘
went through a whole lot of trouble, and done spread a whole lot of bull
想尽一切办法
to purchase this lovely lady right here,
事实上... 布隆希达才是你相中的黑奴
it would appear that Broomhilda is, in fact... the right nigger.
如果你们想带着布隆希达离开糖果农场
And if y'all want to leave Candyland with Broomhilda,
价钱就是一万二
the price is $12,000.
我是否可以理解为你比较喜欢"不买就滚"式的谈判?
And I take it you prefer the "take it or leave it" style of negotiation?
的确如此 医生
Yes, I do, doctor.
要知道 根据奇克索县的法律
You see, under the laws of Chickasaw County,
布隆希达是我的财产
Broomhilda here is my property.
而我可以对自己的财产任意处置!
And I can choose to do with my property whatever I so desire!
如果你们觉得我对这个黑奴...
And if y'all think my price...
开的价钱太离谱...
for this nigger here is too steep...
那我想做的是...
what I'm gonna desire to do is...
拿起这把榔头 活活把她砸死!
take this goddamn hammer here and beat her ass to death with it!
- 就在你们两个面前!  - 坐下 大个子
- Right in front of both y'all!  - Easy, big fella.
然后我们就能一起检查布隆希达头骨里的那三个凹陷了!
Then we can examine the three dimples inside Broomhilda's skull!
那你怎么说 医生? 怎样?
Now, what's it gonna be, doc? Huh?
你怎么说?
What's it gonna be?
我的手能不能离开桌面 拿一下皮夹呢?
May I lift the hands off the tabletop in order to remove my billfold?
当然可以
Yes, you may.
一万二
That 12.
成交!
Sold!
恭喜这位胡子精致的先生
To the man with the exceptional beard
以及他的烂黑奴拍得
and his unexceptional nigger.
- 莫吉先生  - 什么事 卡尔文?
- Mr. Moguy.  - Yes, Calvin?
能请你给这两位先生一张一万两千美元的收据吗?
Will you make these gentlemen a receipt for $12,000, please?
一万二
$12,000.
和你们的交易真是愉快
It was a pleasure doing business with y'all.
先生们...
Now, gentlemen...
请随我到客厅...
if you care to join me in the parlor...
享用清蛋糕
we will be serving white cake.
干得好 卡尔文
Well done, Calvin.
抱歉 能停一下吗 女士?
Excuse me. Excuse me, ma'am?
能不能别再谈贝多芬的曲子了? 把手从竖琴上拿开!
Could you please stop playing Beethoven? Take your hands off the harp!
医生!
Doctor!
- 医生 你不能进去!  - 史蒂芬 史蒂芬
- Doctor, you can't go in there!  - Stephen, Stephen.
他进那里又没什么事
He ain't got no business going in there.
让他去吧
Let it be.
他就是有点心烦 随他去吧
He's just a little upset, that's all.
我来处理
I'll handle this.
清蛋糕?
White cake?
我不吃甜食 谢谢
I don't go in for sweets, thank you.
好吧
Hm.
你现在满心都在怨恨我 是吧?
You brooding about me getting the best of you, huh?
事实上 我在想你今天喂了狗的那个可怜黑奴
Actually, I was thinking of that poor devil you fed to the dogs today.
达达尼安
D'Artagnan.
我在想大仲马对此会有何看法
And I was wondering what Dumas would make of all this.
谁?
Come again?
亚历山大·仲马 "三剑客"的作者
Alexandre Dumas. He wrote The Three Musketeers.
对 就是他 医生
Yes, of course, doctor.
我想你一定很赞赏他
I figured you must be an admirer.
都用他作品的主角来命名自己的奴隶了
You named your slave after his novel's lead character.
如果亚历山大·仲马今天在这儿
Now, if Alexandre Dumas had been there today,
我在想他会怎么说
I wonder what he would have made of it.
你觉得他不会同意吗?
You doubt he'd approve, huh?
没错 他的同意那就怪了
Yes. His approval would be a dubious proposition at best.
法国人都很心软
Soft-hearted Frenchie.
亚历山大·仲马是黑人
Alexandre Dumas is black.
- 这是布隆希达的文件吗?  - 没错
- Are these Broomhilda's papers?  - Yes, they are.
- 我能看看吗?  - 当然
- May I?  - Of course.
谢谢
Thank you.
这是她的出售证明 历任主人的清单
That is her bill of sale, her ownership history,
当然还有她的卖身契 医生
and, of course, her freedom papers, doctor.
能借我笔和墨水吗?
Would you have ink and pen for me?
- 就在那边的小桌子上  - 谢谢
- Right over there on that little table.  - Thank you.
谢谢
Thank you.
布隆希达·沙夫特女士...
Broomhilda Von Shaft...
你自由了
consider yourself a free woman.
坎迪先生...
Mr. Candie...
通常我会说"再会"
normally, I would say auf wiedersehen.
但事实上 "再会"带有"期待再次相会"的意思
But since what auf Wiedersehen actually means is "till I see you again"
而我一点都不想再见到你
and since I never wish to see you again,
所以我要说 永别了
to you, sir... I say, "goodbye."
我们走吧
Let's go.
快点
Come on.
等一下 医生
One more moment, doctor!
什么事?
What?
我们南部有个惯例...
It's a custom here in the South...
两方生意谈拢之后握手
once a business deal is concluded that the two parties shake hands.
以表美好的祝愿
It implies good faith.
- 但我可不是南方人  - 但你现在...
- I'm not from the South.  - But you are...
在我家 医生
in my house, doctor.
- 所以我坚持要握手  - 坚持?
- So I'm afraid I must insist.  - Insist?
坚持什么? 和我握手?
On what? That I shake your hand?
哦 这样的话 我恐怕要坚持不握手了
Oh, then I'm afraid I must insist in the opposite direction.
- 你知道我怎么看你吗?  - 你怎么看我?
- You know what I think you are?  - What you think I am?
不知道
No, I don't.
- 你当你废材一个  - 而我觉得你是个无耻的赢家
- I think you are a bad loser.  - And I think you're an abysmal winner.
虽然如此 但在奇克索县 不握手
Nevertheless, here in Chickasaw County, a deal ain't done
生意就不算完成
until the two parties have shook hands.
就算签好了法律文件 也没用...
Even after all that paper signin', don't mean shit...
因为你不握手
you don't shake my hand.
如果我过来握手 你会不要这12000美金?
If I don't shake your hand, you're gonna throw away $12,000?
我不这么觉得
I don't think so.
普奇先生?
Mr. Pooch?
在这个德国佬跟我握手之前 如果她敢动一下的话
If she tries to leave here before this nigger-loving German shakes my hand,
把她给我废了
you cut her ass down.
你真的想要我和你握手吗?
You really want me to shake your hand?
必须如此
I insist.
既然你这么说了
If you insist.
天啊! 卡尔文!
No! Calvin!
卡尔文!
Calvin!
对不起 我说过别握的
I'm sorry. I couldn't resist.
黑鬼发疯了! 救命啊!
Nigger's gone crazy! Help!
救命啊 他大开杀戒啦!
Help, he's killing everyone!
啊!
Ah!
见鬼了..!
Holy...!
操! 混蛋!
Shit! Son of a bitch!
见鬼! 我操...!
Damn it! Fuckin'...!
- 给我...!
- Get the...!
见鬼 混蛋!
Damn it, son of a bitch!
什么...? 见鬼了...
What...? Fucking...
操蛋操蛋!
Goddamn it!
这他妈是什么情况?
What the fuck is going on?
你打到我了!
You shot me!
- 你个没脑子的白痴!  - 对不住了 杰西!
- You stupid son of a bitch!  - Sorry, Jessie!
哪个操蛋的给黑鬼枪的啊?
Who the fuck gave a nigger a goddamn gun?
瞄低点!
Aim low!
黑鬼! 天杀的...!
Nigger! Gonna kill...!
天啊! 我的天啊!
God! Oh, my God!
操他妈的!
Motherfucker!
见鬼!
Shit!
Shit.
停火!
Hold your fire!
他妈的 停火!
Stop shootin', goddamn it!
姜戈!
Django!
搞毛啊?
What?
我们抓到你女人了!
We got your woman!
比利·克劳什拿枪顶着她脑袋呢
Billy Crash here got his pistol upside her head.
你不给我现身投降的话
You don't stop all that carrying on,
到时候打爆她的头
he gonna blow her goddamn brains out.
我说出来不是吓吓人 牛仔 我说到做到
And that ain't no threat, horse boy. That there is a promise.
或者..
Or...
你投降 把枪扔出来...
you can give up, throw your gun out...
- 我们保证不杀希尔迪  - 屁话!
- we won't kill Hildi.  - Horseshit!
我说真的 姜戈 我对天发誓
Honest lnjun, Django. I swear 'fore God.
你缴械 我们不会伤害她的
You give up, ain't no harm gonna come to her.
我难道平白无故相信你个黑鬼说的话啦?
And I'm supposed to believe your black ass?
要我说 我可不管你信不信
Personally, I don't give a good goddamn what you believe or don't believe!
我相信 你要是十秒钟内不投降
I believe if you don't give up in the next ten seconds,
就要这婊子脑袋开花! 信不信由你!
we gonna blow this bitch's brains out! Believe that!
别这样 你别管我
Don't do it. You give me up.
- 六!  - 随我去好了
- Six!  - Just let me go.
- 七!  - 他们人太多了
- Seven!  - They got too much.
- 姜戈  - 八了!
- Django.  - Eight!
- 我爱你  - 九!
- I love you.  - Nine!
- 等一下!  - 不
- Hold it!  - No.
我缴械投降
I give up.
我听不见你说什么 黑鬼
I can't hear you, nigger.
我说 我缴械投降
I said I give up!
不啊!
No!
不要啊!
太阳上山 该起床了 黑鬼
Cock-a-doodle-do, nigger.
你是个赏金猎人咯?
So y'all bounty hunters, huh?
我就知道你们有什么不可告人的秘密
I knew there was something fishy about y'all.
我们在你的鞍囊里...
We found your wanted posters...
找到了你们的悬赏令和记账本
and book of figures in your saddlebags.
但我不得不说...
I got to say...
我之前从来没听说黑人做赏金猎人的
I ain't never heard of no black bounty hunter before.
黑人收钱杀白人? 这个怎么合逻辑呢?
Black boy paid to kill white men? How'd you like that line of work?
好像你们做得还不错的样子啊?
Probably pretty good while it lasted, huh?
跟蛋蛋说拜拜吧 黑仔
Time to say good night to them nuts, blackie.
数到三啊 一...
On three. One...
我刀快 二...
I got you. Two...
冷静点 就一下啊
Calm down, now, here it comes.
队长?
Captain?
劳拉小姐要见你
Miss Lara want to see you.
是说和老主人葬礼有关的事情
Something to do with the Old Man's funeral.
哦 另外她不想让姜戈挨那一刀了
Oh, and she changed her mind 'bout snipping Django.
她打算把他送给勒坎·迪奇的人
She gonna give him to the LeQuint Dickey people.
她的主意改得真是及时
Well, she didn't waste a minute telling me.
让人失望啊
How disappointing.
你走的话
You leavin'.
这些就是你随身带的了
This here what you take with you.
你个黑仔的一通乱打 让那群管事的人
Your black ass has been all them motherfuckers at The Big House
讨论了好些时候
could talk about for the last few hours.
好像那群白人就天生没什么好想法
Seem like white folk ain't never had a bright idea in they life
他们脑子里都是 把你杀了了事
was coming up with all kinds of ways to kill your ass.
说一句 他们脑子里想的 都是怎么处置你那玩意儿
Now, mind you, most of them ideas had to do with fuckin' with your fun parts.
这看上去是个好主意 不过实际上...
Now, that may seem like a good idea, but truth is...
当黑鬼被切了蛋蛋之后
when you snip a nigger's nuts,
大多数流血至死 哦.. 大概流7分钟的样子
most of them bleed out in, oh, about, hm... seven minutes.
大部分的人
Most of 'em.
好吧 绝大多数
Well, more than most.
所以我说 还不够狠
Then I says: "Shitfire.
我们卖给勒坎·迪奇的黑鬼比这惨多了
The niggers we sell to LeQuint Dickey got it worse than that."
他们还说 我们鞭死他算了
And they still sayin', "Let's whip him to death."
或者 让他跟曼丁哥打一架 把他喂斯通塞弗家的狗
Or "Throw him to the Mandingos." "Feed him to Stonesipher's dogs."
我说 这有什么特别的呢?
And I said, "What's so special about that?
这事我们不是常做吗
We do that shit all the time.
见了个鬼了 我们卖给勒坎·迪奇的黑鬼比这可苦多了
Hell's bells, the niggers we sell to LeQuint Dickey got it worse than that."
你瞧
Lo and behold,
突然间 劳拉小姐想出了一个绝妙的点子
out of nowhere, Miss Lara come up with the bright idea
把你卖给勒坎·迪奇矿场
of giving your ass to the LeQuint Dickey Mining Company.
直到你死的那一天
And as a slave of the LeQuint Dickey Mining Company,
你都是勒坎·迪奇矿场的奴隶
henceforth, till the day you die,
你会一直 每天
all day, every day,
挥着长柄大锤
you will be swinging a sledgehammer,
把大石头敲成小石头
turning big rocks into little rocks.
当你到那边的时候 你不会再有名字
Now, when you get there, they gonna take away your name,
取而代之的是 工作号码和一柄大锤
give you a number and a sledgehammer,
被叫嚣道 还不快去工作!
and say, "Get to work!"
顶一句嘴 他们就割了你的舌头
One word of sass, they cuts out your tongue.
而且他们手脚麻利 你都没机会流很多血
And they good at it too. You won't bleed out.
没错... 他们就是那么麻利
Oh... they does that real good.
他们就这么治你
They gonna work ya.
天天治 每天治 直到你的奄奄一息为止
All day, every day, till your back give out.
到那时候 他们用榔头敲碎你的脑袋
Then they're gonna hit you in the head with a hammer,
再把你扔进黑鬼洞了事
throw your ass down the nigger hole.
这就是你之后的人生 姜戈
And that will be the story of you, Django.
去勒坎·迪奇矿场的路上
记住原则 弗兰奇?
And what's the golden rule, Frankie, eh?
别理那些黑鬼
You don't root abos.
嘿 白人小伙
Hey, white boy.
我说你呢 嘿 白人小伙
I said, hey, white boy.
闭嘴 黑仔 你的话我不感兴趣
Shut up, black. You ain't got nothing to say I want to hear.
你想赚11000美金吗?
How'd you like to make $11,000?
赚什么?
Do what, now?
我说 你想赚11000美金吗? 准确的说 11500美金
I said how'd you like to make $11,000? 11,500, actually.
你他妈在说什么
What the fuck are you talking about?
在糖果农场种植园 藏着价值11500的宝藏
Back there at that plantation, Candyland, there was an $11,500 fortune,
就在那里 而你们刚刚与它失之交臂
just sittin' there. And y'all rode right past it.
你个疯子 黑鬼 我们可不是强盗
You be damned, blackie, we're not bandits.
我可没这么说 这宝藏好就好在 拿它不犯法
I ain't saying that. Nice thing about this fortune is it ain't illegal.
你不是去偷
You can't steal it.
你是要去争取 白人小哥
You got to earn it, white boy.
你有什么要说的 开天窗说亮话
You got something to say, mate, you say it.
糖果农场里的11500美金宝藏
The $11,500 fortune waitin' for you back at Candyland
是捉拿斯密·巴考尔和他的团伙的赏金
is in the form of a "Wanted Dead or Alive" bounty
生死不论
on Smitty Bacall and the Bacall Gang.
谁他妈是斯密·巴考尔啊?
Who the fuck is Smitty Bacall?
斯密·巴考尔是一群马车劫匪的头子 专干杀人越货的勾当
Smitty Bacall is the leader of this murderous gang of stagecoach robbers,
人称巴考尔帮
the Bacall Gang.
活捉或生杀斯密·巴考尔的赏金是7000美金
There's a $7,000 "Wanted Dead or Alive" bounty on him,
他的另外三个同伙 丹迪·迈克尔斯
$1,500 for each of his three accomplices:
杰拉尔德·纳什和疯子克雷格·昆斯
Dandy Michaels, Gerald Nash,
各值1500美金
and Crazy Craig Koons.
他们四个人现在
Now, all four of them gentlemen,
在糖果农场开心得不得了
they back there at Candyland laughing their ass off.
你知道为什么吗? 因为他们刚刚逃过一劫
You know why? 'Cause they just got away with murder.
但他们不会得意太久
But it ain't got to be that way.
你和你的伙计们 可以杀个回马枪 把那钱给赚了
You and your mates, y'all can ride back there and y'all can go get that money.
他们到底做了什么事情?
What'd these jokers do again?
那群混蛋 他们杀无辜的人
These sons of bitches, they killed innocent people.
抢劫马车 专杀无辜的白人
Stagecoach robbery. Innocent white people.
我袋子里就有通缉令 我拿给你看
I got the handbill right here in my pocket, if you let me get it.
拿出来
Get it out.
悬赏 生死不论 斯密·巴考尔以及斯密·巴考尔帮
"Wanted. Dead or alive. Smitty Bacall and the Smitty Bacall Gang."
- 但就你个奴隶  - "因其犯下杀人..."
- But you're a slave.  - "For murder..."
- 我才他妈不是奴隶  - "抢劫马车"
- I ain't no goddamn slave.  - "...and stagecoach robbery."
我说话他妈地像是个奴隶吗?
Do I sound like a fuckin' slave?
- "斯密·巴考尔悬红7000美金"  - 嗯?
- "$7,000 for Smitty Bacall."  - Hm?
- 还真值钱啊  - 我是个赏金猎人
- That's a shitload.  - I'm a bounty hunter.
昨天 我还是自由之身
Yesterday, as a free man,
我和我德国的白人搭档金·舒尔茨博士
I rode into Candyland on a horse with my German white partner,
骑马进了糖果农场
Dr. King Schultz.
我们从德州一路追查巴考尔帮到奇克索县
We tracked the Bacall Gang all the way from Texas to Chickasaw County.
我们终于发现那群混蛋在糖果农场隐姓埋名
We finally found their ass layin' low in Candyland.
他们杀进去要取他们首级 但事与愿违
We went in there to get 'em, things went sour,
我搭档被杀 卡尔文·坎迪被打死
my partner got killed, Calvin Candie got shot,
那里的人把怒气都发在我身上 所以我就落到了现在这下场
then everybody there decided to blame me, so here I am.
但你们知道 我是被冤枉的
But y'all know I ain't on that manifest.
你们都知道 我不应该走这趟的
And all y'all know I ain't supposed to be on this trip.
但那边的四个人 他们仍被通缉中
But them four men is still back there, they're still wanted,
11500赏金唾手可得 他们肯定想不到
and that 11,500 is up for grabs, and the last thing they'd expect
你们会杀个回马枪 去取赏金
is y'all ridin' back in there and gettin' it.
到底怎么说?
What's the deal?
你告诉我他们是谁 我放你走?
You tell us who they are and we turn you loose?
不行 不行 我不会告诉你他们是谁
No, no, no, no. I ain't gonna tell you who they are.
但你给我把手枪 一匹马
But, you give me a pistol, one of them horses,
11500美金里面的500块 我就指给你们看
and $500 of that 11,500, and I'll point 'em out to you.
这通缉令是真的
This is a real handbill.
就算这是真的通缉令
Now just 'cause it's a real handbill
也不代表刚才那顿叽里呱啦是真的
doesn't mean that other bunch of malarkey is.
为什么奴隶身上会有"死活不论"通缉令呢?
Now why would a slave have a "Wanted Dead or Alive" handbill in his pocket?
那黑仔昨天才到糖果农场的吗?
Did that black ride into Candyland yesterday?
好吧 我再问一遍
All right, I'm gonna ask you again.
我要你们记好了 我可不喜欢骗子啊
I want you to remember, I don't like liars.
他是不是糖果庄园的奴隶
Is he a Candyland slave,
还是他跟一个白人骑马路过的?
or did he ride in with a white man on a horse yesterday?
是的 他们他和一个白人骑马
Yeah. They walked us from the Greenville auction,
从格林维尔拍卖行路过
and he rode in on a horse with a white man.
那个黑人是那白人的奴隶吗?
Now this white man, was the black his slave?
他才不是什么奴隶
He weren't no slave.
- 你他妈确定吗?  - 太他妈确定了
- You fuckin' sure about that?  - Damn sure.
- 糖果农场到底发生了什么?  - 一堆乱射
- What happened over in Candyland?  - Bunch-a shootin'.
到处都在开枪
Massa got shot.
- 谁打了他?  - 那个德国人
- Who shot him?  - The German.
他为什么这么做?
Why'd he do that?
那黑鬼和那德国人伪装成奴隶贩子 但他们不是
Nigger and the German was actin' like they were slavers but they wasn't.
- 那他们到底是干什么的?  - 赏金猎人
- Well, what were they?  - Bounty hunters.
我操 罗伊 我感觉这次大大的有戏 伙计
Fuck me, Roy. I mean, this could be big, mate.
小伙子 这是就这么办了
Well, smoke, you got a deal.
- 我就一个条件  - 什么条件?
- I got one more condition.  - What's that?
等我们到了 该下手的时候...
When we get there, when time come...
- 你让我帮你除了他们  - 啊...
- you let me help you kill 'em.  - Hey...
你还真会说笑
you're a funny bugger.
- 给他松绑吧  - 好类
- Cut him loose.  - Yeah, yeah.
这是就这样定下来 黑仔
You got yourself a deal, blackie.
那就这么定下了 伙计
You got yourself a deal, mate.
嘿!
Hey!
你这黑人还真有趣啊
You're all right for a black fella.
哦 好了
Oh, yeah.
好了 这就好了 伙计
There we go. There you go, mate.
好的
Yeah.
那就把那边驼东西的马给你啦
We're gonna give you that packhorse over there.
它们驮的是什么啊?
What them saddlebags got in 'em?
- 炸药  - 不行 我可不骑驮着
- Dynamite.  - No. I ain't ridin' no horse
炸药的马
with no goddamn dynamite on its back.
这可以理解
I can understand that.
弗兰奇 你把马上驮的东西卸下来
Frankie, why don't you take them sticks off that horse
放到黑鬼的笼子里面
and stick 'em in the nigger cage.
给你们黑人小伙带了点炸药玩玩
A little dynamite for you black fellas to play with.
佛洛伊德 车上的枪是你拿着的吧?
Now, Floyd, you got that rifle up on the wagon, don't ya?
是啊 没错
Yeah, right.
你要不把你枪和枪壳给他?
Why don't you give him your gun and gun belt?
好嘞
Righto.
别把这东西掉了 懂吗?
Now, don't drop the fuckin' thing, all right?
我刚刚修过准心 他们刚刚调准
I've just had the sights fixed and they're perfect.
知道了知道了
Oh, that's good to know.
把那堆炸药扔给我
Throw me up that dynamite.
- 杰克!  - 什么事?
- Jake!  - Yeah?
出去看看 外面这群狗到底发什么疯!
Get out there and see what's wrong with them goddamn dogs!
为达达尼安报仇 你们这些混蛋!
D'Artagnan, motherfuckers!
- 嘿!
- Hey!
再会
Auf Wiedersehen.
是我 宝贝
It's me, baby.
科拉 给我们准备咖啡好吗?
Cora, would you prepare us some coffee?
示巴 你去帮她
Sheba, you help her.
这边
Come on.
哦 你们迟早要和卡尔文在天堂见面的
Oh, y'all gonna be together with Calvin in the by-and-by, all right.
只是可能比料想的早一点了
Just a bit sooner than y'all was expectin'.
比利·克劳什
Billy Crash.
我们说到哪儿了?
Now, where were we?
哦 对了
Oh, that's right.
上次我见你的时候 你的手碰到我的...
Last time I seen you, you had your hands on my...
姜戈! 你个黑畜生!
Django! You black son of a bitch!
我的名字你配你叫 乡巴佬
The D is silent, hillbilly.
哦 不!
Oh, no!
现在呢 黑人朋友们
Now, all you black folks,
我建议你们远离那些白人朋友稍微远一点
I suggest you get away from all these white folks.
没说你 史蒂芬
Not you, Stephen.
你给我站着别动
You right where you belong.
科拉 你走之前 能和劳拉小姐道个别吗?
Cora, before you go, will you tell Miss Lara goodbye?
- 什么?  - 我是说 "跟劳拉小姐道个别"
- Do what now?  - I said, "Tell Miss Lara goodbye."
拜 劳拉小姐
Bye, Miss Lara.
你们两个可以走了
Y'all two run along now.
史蒂芬 你觉得我的衣服怎么样?
Stephen, how you like my new duds?
之前我还真不知道黑紫色穿我身上不错
You know, before now I didn't know that burgundy was my color.
我数着你开了六枪 黑鬼
I count six shots, nigger.
架不住我有两把枪 黑鬼
I count two guns, nigger.
你说 在这片种植园呆了76年
You said in 76 years on this plantation,
你见过黑人受过各种各样的罪
you seen all manner-a shit done to niggers.
但我发现 你没提过膑刑
But I notice, you didn't mention kneecappin'.
老天爷啊! 混蛋! 操个蛋!
Oh, God! Motherfucker! Damn it!
七十六年了 史蒂芬
Seventy-six years, Stephen.
你经手了多少黑人啊?
How many niggers you think you see come and go, huh?
七千个?
Seven thousand?
八千个?
Eight thousand?
九千个?
Nine thousand?
九千九百九十九个?
Nine thousand, nine hundred and ninety-nine?
卡尔文·坎迪说的一切
Every single word that came out of Calvin Candie's mouth
满嘴都是谎言
was nothin' but horseshit.
但他说对了一件事 我就是那个万里挑一的黑仔
But he was right about one thing: I am that one nigger in 10,000.
你个混蛋!
You son of a bitch!
You motherfucker!
哦 老天爷啊 赐我力量除了这个黑鬼吧!
Oh, sweet Jesus, let me kill this nigger!
你会遭报应的 姜戈!
You ain't gonna get away with this, Django!
他们会找到你的
They gonna catch your black ass.
到时候悬赏的就是你的人头了 黑鬼
You gonna be on the wanted posters now, nigger.
赏金猎人会找上门的
The bounty hunters gonna be lookin' for you.
你可以逃 黑鬼 但他们会找到你的!
You can run, nigger, but they gonna find your ass!
等他们找到你的时候 我对天发誓 等他们找到你的时候!
And when they do, oh, Lord, what they gonna do to your ass!
他们不会简单的杀了你完事 黑鬼!
They ain't gonna just kill you, nigger!
你会被虐的很惨的!
You done fucked up!
这片庄园 黑鬼!
This Candyland, nigger!
你毁不掉这片庄园!
You can't destroy Candyland!
只要我们在这里! 糖果农场就会一直在这里!
We been here! There's always gonna be a Candyland!
黑鬼枪法再厉害 也杀不光所有的白人!
Can't no nigger gunfighter kill all the white folks in the world!
他们会把你揪出来的!
They gonna find your black ass!
姜戈!
Django!
你个不知天高地厚的...
You uppity son of a...
嘿 小坏蛋
Hey, Little Trouble Maker.
嘿 大坏蛋
Hey, Big Trouble Maker.
你知道他们会叫你什么吗? "南部最快的枪"
You know what they are going to call you? "The fastest gun in the South."
我们走吧
Let's get outta here.
别走 还有一下段哦
这黑鬼到底是谁啊?
Who was that nigger?
-=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/=-
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 景鲤
翻译: 爱FAFA的萌 Mabb 司嘉译 蓝风 影子 RK翔
校对: 被解救的UU 柚子茶